[Music]
Hey. Hey.
Hey.
[Music]
Heat. Hey. Hey. Hey.
Hello and welcome to the latest episode
rather. unscheduled episode of the Ask a
Visit Show. We're doing this on a
Sunday. Uh I had to postpone it because
I was kind of unwell. So, thank you to
to those of all of all those of you who
sent in your wishes. I really appreciate
that. I'm much better now. And uh here
we go. So, uh let us see who all is
there on the live chat. I can see
geopolitical dub. I can see Shamik Bring
Sheshnik Dak Vora Jo G Joy Hind Joy
Nagaland Animesh Paul. Uh Smen
Goray
Chandra Dak Global Citizens Shogun
Ajinkaw God was alive Yan Kumar Bjel
Mystic SK Saint Crocodile Mahita
Bushetti Mr. Jam Sharma J Singh Vikash
XN
uh Hirkumar Patel Mr. 88 W gada
geopolitical dub from indor Himmanu Ma
uh Shivan Shankar Roshi Shete Jesh Singh
Anonymous scientist Kushwaha Mlevin
Mystic SK Mr. Jam uh Vamshi Khale, Adita
Singh, Brayesh, Light, Yagami, Harsh,
Ahabijit, M Alan, J Victor, Hitan,
Chumat, Naresh, Mota, Unknown, um
Gorish, KB, Samripati, Chitan, Araadya,
Sagar, Gare uh who else do we have? Aaya
Rupal, Kakashi, Hataki, uh, Chhat
Kashup, Sager, Torat, Prasad, Dalal,
Prane, Paul from Kolkata, Parikit, Vij,
Shivan Shanker and everybody else. So,
thank you so much for being on this live
chat and uh let us see what questions we
have. Please get going. Let's have the
questions. I'll take this I'll make it
as long as
possible and uh yeah maybe we'll we'll
have another 3-hour
session. Let's see what else what
questions do we have? I'll obviously
first take the the live what do we call
it super chats. Kumar Kesh says downfall
of tech innovation in science medical
and many started before Arabic or and
Turk invasion that is that a question or
is that a statement? It's a question. So
did the downfall of tech innovation
start before all this stuff that made us
susceptible as previous attempts had
failed? No, it is not the downfall of
something that that had that was the
cause of the success of the Turk
invasions. It was not that the cause of
the success of the Arabic and Turk
invasions was the lack of political
unity in India at that particular point
in time. We did not have a single empire
that ruled us, a single emperor that
ruled us. uh the the Morian era was a
time when we had a single empire empire
that ruled over the whole subcontinent.
The Gupta empire the Gupta era was
another era when you had a single empire
that rule over the entire subcontinent.
During the time when the Turks and the
Arabs started invading Arabs first then
Turks we were a fragmented subcontinent.
We were a single civilization with lots
of different kingdoms and that's why
that succeeded. The tech innovation
science etc was going on pretty well.
There was no downfall in that absolutely
not not at all. We still had the great
universities and all that. So there was
no such issue as such. It was the lack
of political unity that was the cause of
our downfall. Sheshnik says tell us more
about Bajira Peshwa of the Marata
Empire. Peshawa Bajiro the first. He was
born when
around the beginning of the of the 18th
century, right? And he and he lived only
38 39 years. and uh he was the the
Peshwa who established the supremacy of
the Marata Empire in India and uh yeah I
mean I haven't studied his life and
history in great detail but that's what
I can tell you the first the greatest of
the Marata Peshwas and it is his career
and his string of incredible victories
over all the all the foreign occupiers
of India that led to the Marata
supremacy and the revival of of Indian
civilization and the establishment of a
single empire. over India. So yeah
that's Bajirov Peshwa the great J Singh
thank you so much. Thank you very much
sir. So now let's take some questions
from the regular chat.
Um Shri Ramchandra Namaha says what is
electronic warfare examples? Electronic
warfare for example if you have a
fighter let's say you have fighter
planes going over Pakistan you know you
want to destroy some more terrorist uh
hideouts and terrorist infrastructure.
So let's say u you want to send fighter
planes into Pakistan but what if the
Pakistanis
u you
know what if the Pakistanis will
um now let me think of a proper scenario
for this electronic warfare. So there
are multiple kinds of electronic
warfare. One is when a fighter, you
know, when when an adversarial aircraft
comes into your territory and wants you
wants to attack your targets, you
interfere with their electronics so that
they don't get a proper view of the
battle space. Their radars don't work
properly. Uh their their guidance
systems get jammed and their missiles
are not able to locate the targets.
They're not able to access the GPS or
whatever is happening. That is one
example of electronic warfare that that
happens. Um that's a defensive measure.
For example, when you are defending
against an enemy, then when you are when
you are actually going and you are
attacking the enemy, for example, then
you want to jam their systems, their
defensive systems. So you may have some
electronic warfare aircraft that come
with your fighter aircraft and who will
jam all your all your all your enemies
uh defensive infrastructure and and
their electronic systems. Then you have
systems like uh for example
uh uh anti-radiation
missiles. So there are so how does the
how do does the Pakistani air defense
system detect Indian aircraft? They have
radars, right? So what are radars? They
send out electromagnetic signals. That's
radiation. Electromagnetic
electromagnetic radiation. So if you
have ARM missiles, anti-radiation
missiles, these missiles will look
exactly for such transmissions and they
will home in on the source of the
signals and wipe them out. So these are
different examples of electronic
warfare. Right. Okay.
Um Prashant says Pakistan general 100
died in Brahmo that enter half a meter
hole. Is it really happened? Yeah, it
apparently look I don't know how many
100 generals I don't think Pakistan is
Pakistan has a 100 generals you what one
hears they had some a number of officers
maybe 40 maybe 100 whatever it is but
yes you had a an entrance that was about
four 45 cm wide apparently and the
Brahos hit that so as you can see I mean
try try
hitting those of you who have played
cricket it's a 22 yard pitch right in
you're bowling and when you when you're
bowling, when you're practicing, you put
a coin on the other end of of the pitch
where you want the ball to pitch and try
and hit that how how you'll very quickly
see how difficult it is to accurately
hit the one coin on the pitch. That's
over 22 yards. That's about 20 m, right?
The bramos is launched over distances of
hundreds of kilometers and then you hit
a target that is 45 cm wide. That's what
we did. So outstanding. I think it
really happened. Yes, all these facts
are slowly emerging out in the public
domain. It is it's it's great to see
this. Shivar Rajput says if Subhash
Chundra Bose was PM, India might have
followed a China-like model, fast
growth, less democracy. I mean, just
like the CCP, India might have followed
that for 20 years, maybe more, maybe
less. Uh Mr. Bose's plan was to do that
for 20
years. So, India would have been a
totally different beast if Mr.
Subbasendra Bose had become the leader
of India. Whether it's we need not have
had a prime minister at that at that
point in time. He would have been the
president of India. Why would he need to
be a prime minister at the head of a
council of ministers and with a
Westminster style system? It would have
been a proper clean
dictatorship. Okay, with the king at the
top and a council of ministers who will
do what they told and who will give
their inputs to the to the king and that
sort of thing. That's what what it would
have been like. He would not have been
the prime minister. He would have been
the emperor of India or the dictator of
India. Fast growth less democracy like
the CCP. That's that was his plan but as
you know didn't work
out Pawar says why is it that throughout
history one man often thinks differently
and changes the world. What sets them
apart from everybody else? It's just the
way it is. It's many people disagree
with this perspective the great man
theory of history. But see the most
people are mediocre. the the the the
word the term mediocre means average. It
doesn't mean bad. It means average. Most
people are average because that's what
average means, right? It means like
everybody else. And it's always the
0.1% who think really differently and
who have the genius to do things which
others can't. And that genius is what's
required for a real growth and real
change in in history. So that's just the
way it is. It's always the ordinary
person can't really take the world by it
throat and and force it to change. They
don't want things to change. The
ordinary person is happy with the the
way things are. It's only those small
number of people who are not satisfied
with the shape of things and who want
things to be better. They are the ones
who change the world. Sometimes it's for
the good, sometimes it's for not so
good. But that's how it works. What sets
them apart? it what sets them apart is
that they are definitely more
intelligent and they have way more
perseverance and willpower and they have
agency. They will not take no for an
answer. They will find a way to get
things done. That's what sets them
apart. Okay. Dhir Kamat says, "Has in
has America successfully infiltrated
India now with the approval of Starlink?
What can India do to safeguard its
sovereignty?"
Yes, with the approval of Starlink and
once the Starlink beams start and once
Starling Starlink starts beaming its
signals into India, yes, it's
infiltration of India.
Absolutely. What can India do to
safeguard its
sovereignty? Disapprove Starlink. Tell
them you no longer have the right
license. Sorry. Anyway, this is a good
time to disapprove Starlink to revoke
the license because Elon Musk is no
longer on favorable terms with Donald
Trump. This is a good time to do it. So
I would uh you know recommend to the
government of India uh grab this
opportunity. Elon Musk and Donald Trump
are fighting like little children like
school children. They are fighting like
uh like like like uh recently broken up
uh
lovers and they're fighting very
publicly and they're th throwing all
kinds of very dirty allegations at each
other and Donald Trump is a president.
he'll be happy if somebody uh does uh
you know if if something like this is
done he'll be okay with it. So I would
say this is a great time for India to
use whatever technical reason or
whatever it is to say that sorry
Starlink your license whatever was
approved is now
disapproved. I think it's a it's the
right time to do that. And then
long-term what India should do is India
should have its own version of a
satellite internet you know internet
beaming satellite
constellation which would be launched by
ISRO and maybe if the geo folks are not
willing to do it maybe somebody else
will be willing to do it maybe Adani
will do it I think Adani as a company is
way more aligned with India's national
interest than the other other companies
if you look at Adani's track record they
have this track record longstanding
track record of always taking up
projects that align with India's
national and geopolitical interests. So
maybe something like this needs to
happen, right? That's what India needs
to do to safeguard its sovereignty and
edge Starlink out in internationally,
globally by putting up a better
alternative to Starling. That's what
India needs to do. Maybe this can be
done over a 5year time horizon. Nothing
not longer than that. First step, please
revoke this license that you've given to
Starlink. Mr. Ediator says, "Thoughts on
MAGA civil war?
I mean, it's crazy. Donald Trump is
probably the most
unpreential president in uh president in
US
history. So juvenile, so childish. And
Elon Musk is the same kind of
individual. Extremely big egos and
they're fighting like children in
public, fighting on
Twitter. I mean, is that how you behave?
and Elon Musk. I mean, both have a
certain point to to what they are doing.
I mean, Donald Trump is I'm the
president of the US and you better get
in line and so on so forth, right? Elon
Musk is that you know what, I am way
richer than you. I'm way more successful
than you. You're just a real estate
developer, somebody who constructed
buildings in New York City. I am a tech
genius. I have Tesla. I have Starling. I
have this. I have that. I have Solar
City and so on and so forth. I am the
richest man in in probably in the past
2000 whatever time right and so on. So I
am better than you I'm greater than you
and that sort of thing. So both have
these big egos and Elon Musk is unhappy
that he has been elbowed out of the
cabinet. He no longer has access to the
White House. The moment he's out he
starts moaning about Trump. It's
incredible if he knew that Trump let's
say like he claims like he the
allegation he's made is that Trump is
Trump features on the Epstein files.
Well, if he knew that, then why didn't
he speak about this before? It was all
fine as long as Trump gave him what he
wanted. The moment Trump doesn't give
him what he wants, he'll reveal this. I
mean, do you also have any principles?
If he really is is is featured on the
Epstein file, they should whether Trump
is on your side or not, you should
reveal
it. So, yeah, it's it's entertaining,
it's fun, and maybe there's something in
it for us. Baratia says if nothing can
ex exceed light speed in space do we
know that if the space itself is
expanding faster than light speed any
scientifically testable data supporting
this sawmath equations
um if nothing can exceed light speed in
space do we know if the space itself is
expanding faster space itself is
expanding faster than light speed there
is something called the Hubble constant
H0 which has a certain value. Let's
let's Google let's quickly Google up the
value. What's the value of the Hubble
constant and that will tell you what
this is an experimentally observed
number. It's not something that comes
out of theory. It comes out of
experimental observations. Hubble
constant constant. What's the value?
H0 by what's the what's the value?
What's the value? Hubble tension we
don't want to talk about. Okay, there
are two values. One is around 60 and one
is around 70 something.
Um okay I'm not interested in the Hubble
constant at this point in time
value or values okay 64 and 7 67 and 74
okay there are two values that that's
the whole matter of the Hubble tension
we'll not go into that but let's say
it's around 70 kilometers per second per
mega parc okay 60 uh sorry around 70
kilometers/s per mega pars so the more
mega parc you add to it the more the
faster the space is expanding this is
experimentally observed. There are there
are no math math equations then that
tell us this. Okay. So if you
extrapolate this over very large
distances you will find that space
itself is expanding faster than faster
than light. Super lumininal
expansion and yet it does not in any way
break the laws of physics. It doesn't uh
break the break the theory of
relativity because it is not something
that is expanding inside of space or or
traveling inside of space faster than
light which is not allowed. It is
spacetime itself that's expanding faster
than light which is
allowed. So this is all based on
experimental evidence of of the the red
of the of the red ships of of galaxies
that are as far away as can be observed.
And yeah, so and there's the Hubble
tension issue which is a whole different
matter which we'll not discuss here.
Sidesh's financial consultancy says my
NL
friend NL okay says they were always
Christian and weren't converted. What's
NL Nagalind I suppose Nagaland says that
okay let's say let's assume it's
Nagaland. He says that they were always
Christian they weren't converted. Can
you shed light as to how long ago the
Nad Nagalan conversion started and how
long does it take to forget your
ancestors were were converted? It takes
5 minutes to to forget your ancestors
were converted as long as there's the
right kind of financial
incentive. Apart from that it takes
maybe two generations to forget. Right?
So what happens when you are converted?
What happens? First of all you have to
burn all the statues of your gods. Burn
them all. Then you have to say that I
only believe in the Lord and Savior
whatever his name is. And you have to
kiss the Bible and you have to do do
Bible classes every day and so on so
forth on a very regular basis. Proper
indoctrination and brainwashing and then
you have to publicly acknowledge and
acknowledge to yourself over and over
again that my ancestors were barbarians
because they they they were polytheists
and so on and that happens over and
over. So after a couple of generations
there is this tremendous hatred these
people have for their ancestry uh and
and their ancestral culture and this
they just don't want to think about it
right and so then they will start
claiming that we were always Christian
we were Christian for the past 3,000
years even before Christianity existed
they'll say the convergence in the
northeast started about um in in
Nagaland it started mo mostly after uh
Javal al- Nero became the prime minister
of India. Before that the British were
trying to do things but after Neu became
the prime minister he opened up he first
of all banned any Hindus to from going
to to Nagaland and in the far east
completely isolated the the what we call
the northeast of India from the rest of
the country. He put a stop on all
development in the place which gave rise
to insurgences all over the place
because when people when there's no
growth there's no development there's no
food there's no prospects for your
children what he will you do right so
that's what Mr. Arrow did and then he
opened the door for American Baptist
missionaries to go all over the place.
So after the 1940s after after around
1950 by about 1980 1990 the whole of
Nagaran mostly was converted. There are
very few people who still practice the
indigenous culture. So imagine from 1950
until now how many years has it been? 80
years but the full uh extent of
Christianization happened by around the
1980s. That's about 50 years ago. So
that's how long it takes to forget that
your ancestors were converted. That's
very sad. They've destroyed beautiful
indigenous culture of Nagal. It's very
sad. It's a tragedy. It's it's uh it's
cultural genocide that was done at the
behest of the great magnificent Mr.
NuKumar Kanishk says why haven't we
explored deep sea organisms and studied
them extensively about their biology?
Can India be a leader in this studies
exploring our deep ocean? Look, I'll
tell you what. When it comes to studies,
scientific studies which explore the
deep ocean, it takes a lot of money to
do that. So, it's only viable if there
is a proper financial incentive, a
return on investment. Let's say you want
to study the deep ocean for
minerals, maybe uh nuggets of various
kinds of metals. Well, that's fun and
you get money out of I mean there's a
return on investment because for example
nickel or whatever other metals which
may not be so readily available on the
surface if they're of the planet if
they're available under ocean under the
water on the surf on on the on the
bottom of the of the ocean well then
prospecting for for such things makes
sense financial economic sense. If you
are digging for let's say oil a thousand
meters under the ocean's uh surface then
it makes sense because oil has a proven
financial value. But when it comes to
studying deep sea
organisms it's going to cost the same
amount of money to study them go all the
way down there and have all these exper
all the instruments and all that which
will look for the organisms and catalog
them and observe their behavior record
everything. It will take a tremendous
amount of money. But what's the return
on investment? Essentially zero, right?
I would love it to happen. I am driven
by a sense of curiosity about the world
and nature and all that. But who's going
to pay pay for that? I mean, I won't be
able to sustain sustainably pay for that
for months and years. I may be able to
pay for it for a week maybe and then I'm
I'll say okay, it's going to burn a hole
through my pockets, right? and I'm not
going to getting any return on that
investment. So do you understand it
doesn't make sense that
way. Any such research needs
to give you return on investment.
Without that it doesn't make financial
sense and then nobody will fund
it especially in a developing country
like
India. Shamit bringing welcome and thank
you so much
sir.
Captain okay no not read that. What stop
US from using Taiwan and Tibet against
China? Well, first of all, the US
doesn't control Tibet. It doesn't own
Tibet. It has absolutely zero influence
or leverage on Tibet. China completely
controls Tibet completely 100%. So
that's number one. Number two, Taiwan.
The US is using Taiwan against China as
as best as it can. Beyond that, what can
it do? Launch a strike on China. Tina
will be wiped out. Taiwan will be wiped
out. Let us think a little from a little
more mature perspective. The US is using
Taiwan as best as it can against uh
China. Please throw light on the
education system of Japan. I hope I'm
Yeah, I'm I'm much better now. Thank
you. The education system of Japan is
extremely rigorous. It is based on a
tremendous amount of study, a lot of
memorization, but also much higher
quality uh system than India's. I mean,
you actually learn stuff there. But one
of the problems in the education system
of Japan is that the the students are
very horribly overburdened. I mean there
is this the I I remember reading this
somewhere in the like 20 30 years ago
there's this saying in Japan okay when
you are when you are let's say in high
school study 5 hours fail study for
sorry not study sleep 5 hours fail sleep
4 hours pass that's how it is it is
crushing it's a tremendous burden and
this is one of the reasons why Japan has
such a low birth rate because people get
burned out by all these
Jo says, "What's happening in LA in the
past 48 hours?" Listen, I have no idea.
I am not a breaking news guy who's going
to scan the news every 15 minutes and
see what's happening. I have no idea
what's happening in LA past 48 hours. I
look at things from a wider lens and a
bigger perspective. I don't I get this
these questions from people a lot of the
time. A lot of the times especially when
I go when I go as a guest in podcast.
Oh, do you know what happened today
morning? Oh, you don't know. I don't
know. I don't care. I don't look at
breaking news every 15 minutes. So I'm
sorry I I'm not aware of what's
happening in LA past 48 hours. If it's
something important, it'll come to my
notice because I have a system for
getting the right kind of information.
The kind of information I require. As
you know, I have this new podcast of
which three episodes have have aired
thus far. It's called Geost Strategy
with Tabit Chava in which I look at the
most important events that are happening
in the world. So I look at I have a
certain set of filters that uh that
ensure that only the right kind of
events come to my come to my notice.
High signal high value events. There's a
lot of noise that's happening in the
world. Oh this thing happened here and
that thing happened and this person said
this and that person said that and so
on. Uh so I'm not sure I I don't look at
look at news every 15 minutes or every
whatever it is. But if the events in LA,
whatever it is, is sufficiently
important, it will be brought to my
notice and then I'll be able to uh tell
you about what's happening. But as of as
of as of right now, I am not aware and
I'm not going to I'm not going to go in.
Okay, let's do it since you've asked. Um
let's quickly take a look at what's
happening in
LA, Los Angeles. What's happening in
Jeset,
etc. 21 hours ago, etc., and so on.
20,000 National Guards. Okay. Some kind
of immigration protests are happening in
Los Angeles. Well, we will see if it's
something important and geopolitically
relevant. I think it's a domestic issue
in the US, but let's see.
Uh Gopol says who destroyed Lalita's
parhaspur? I have no
idea. No idea. A very specific specific
question. Lalita's
paraspur. Um one second. Let me let me
see. Lalitaur.
Lalitaur. What?
Parihaspura founded the city of
Parihaspura etc. uh declined and so
on. Looks like according to what this AI
overview says, it looks like it just
declined over time. Okay, I don't know.
I haven't studied. See, I haven't
studied every single dynasty in the
greatest amount of detail. So, yeah, I
don't know. Don't have the don't have
the right answer for you. Sorry. Uh MK
says, "When Poland can reject
immigrants, why can't the French do that
despite being quasi independent?" Maybe
because Mr. Mako himself is not willing
to reject imig immigrants and maybe
because what you call immigrants are now
French citizens. The the French when it
comes to uh not illegal but legal
immigration into France, it's been
happening for the longest time even way
before the rest of Europe became uh
victim fell fell victim to all this. The
French occupied North Africa, colonized
North Africa for the longest time. And a
lot of these North Africans, they moved
especially Algerians etc. they moved
into various parts of France, especially
in southern France, especially the Kodu
region, especially uh uh which is the
great city
Kodu. Um let's let's go to the map and
I'll tell you immediately which city it
is. Okay, it is one of the great cities,
a beautiful city called Dazu. How come I
don't remember it? It's I
mean one of the great novels features
that city Mi of course Mi a tremendous
amount of immigrants in Maki. It's more
like an immigrant city than than than a
French city today. Like that's what they
say. So these folks are French citizens.
Once you give someone citizenship, you
can't throw them out. And the biggest
problem the French have have is not
illegal immigrants. It's the
citizens. Okay. The French, they can't
do a thing about this now. It's too
late. Sharma says, "Why um how does the
Roman Empire still control the world?
Why the Freemasons, Jesuit, city of
London, Washington DC, roads, Miller,
apparatus, etc. Listen, this is what
they call conspiracy theories. There is
absolutely zero
evidence, zero hard evidence, zero
provable evidence that all of this is
happening, which doesn't mean it's not
happening."
But you see, I'll tell you
something. The Anglo-Saxons, I've said
this a few times, the Anglo-Saxons, one
of the greatest and most remarkable
things they did, okay, the Anglo-Saxons,
is that they hid their instruments of
power. Historically, empires would
flaunt their instruments of power. If
you go to
Parshapur, the ancient capital of the
Persians, they displayed their
instruments of power everywhere. It's
it's a destroyed city. Alexander
destroyed it in one night. He burned it.
Alexander the Greek. But the city still
exists. You can still see the scorch
marks, the burn marks. You can see how
great it used to be. And the Persians,
our Persian cousins, they displayed,
they flaunted the instruments of power
that they had in India. We had empires
that would flaunt and display their
instruments of power. The Romans had
these great columns, the victory
columns, etc. to flaunt the instruments
of power that you know these many
legions we have that did so and so
things and these many ships these many
galleys and so
on but the
Anglo-Saxons they have hidden their
instruments of power they control the
entire world but they hide the fact that
they do they occupy Japan and South
Korea militarily but they have convinced
the entire world that these nations are
vibrant democracies h and they control
the entire west the western part of
Europe through NATO and the EU. These
nations have essentially no sovereignty
at all. But they have convinced the
world that these are you know
beautifully sovereign nations with
vibrant democracies and more these
nations are more democ democratic than
nations like India. This is the power of
propaganda. So that's what the
Anglo-Saxons have done. The Anglo-Saxon
Empire which is now based in Washington
DC. It controls the world but it hides
its instruments of power and it may have
connections with whatever vestigages are
left of the Roman Empire. Some
vestigages are indeed left of the of the
Roman Empire. I mean the western Roman
Empire. I mean the Roman Empire was
destroyed by the Vatican by the church,
right? But then the church became the
inheritor of the of the power the
instruments of power of the Roman
Empire. It happened gradually over time
and then and then it was the church that
was the greatest power in Europe for the
longest
time and some of it may still exist and
some of it may happen via various uh
ways and means including some of the
things that you have mentioned but there
is zero there is absolutely no way of
proving it and that's why these things
are called conspiracy theories. It
doesn't mean they they're false but
there's no way of proving it. So that's
where you have it. That that's that's
what you
have. Okay. Feminist Slayer says some
research papers are claiming that
cockroach
milk that cockroach milk has higher
protein content than cow milk. Is this
some kind of propaganda? Who funds these
studies? I don't know who funds these
studies, but they are enemies of the
human human species, I would say. Okay.
Uh why cockroach milk? Why? Ugh. Yeah, I
I've heard of these things. I've never
read read any of these news research
papers because I value my time. My time
is super valuable. Believe me, if
somebody wants my time, it costs a lot
of
money. So, my time is valuable. I don't
waste it on read reading such research
papers. So, I've not read it. I've only
seen the headlines and that's enough for
me. I'm done with
that. Um, so that's
nonsense and no human should be made to
drink such things. So this is some kind
of new world BS and please stay out of
all this. I would say Parvin Singh says
according to you when will operation
Sindu resume again? There's no way of
predicting when that will resume. The
highest probability is that for the next
3 to 6 months there's going to be you
know increased diplomatic tensions
between India and Pakistan and and water
tensions but there's there's less than a
10% likelihood of uh war fighting
happening again starting again over the
next 3 months I would say beyond that
we'll see beyond that we will see the
Americans are very very very very uh you
know sensitive about
Pakistan yeah because it looks like the
Americans were controlling the Nurh Khan
air base and even Pakistani personnel
were not allowed
inside. And that now raises the question
about what was it that the Pakistanis
tested in
1998? The five or six uh nuclear bombs
they tested. What was that? I am more
and more of the opinion that these were
American nuclear bombs which tells you
that America seems to be India's number
one enemy. No h claiming to be friends
but actions are those of
enemies. Vishal thank you very much sir.
Appreciate
that. MK says is not accepting illegal
immigrants of Poland by by Poland a
concession for being the next Ukraine.
It looks like that Poland is being
positioned as the next frontline state
when it comes to a potential future
hypothetical
westward military incursion. So the so
NATO and the west are tomtoming this
theory that Russia is now that Putin
wants to recreate the USSR and is going
to you know very quickly very soon start
marching
westwards which means that after Ukraine
Poland comes in line in case you want to
see let's take a look at the
map here is the map we go to the right
place immediately so when it it comes to
the geography of Europe Europe, Eastern
Europe, you have Russia, then you have
nations like the Baltic states, Estonia,
Latvia, Lithuania, etc. Then you have uh
Belarus and Ukraine and westwards of
Belarus and Ukraine, you have Poland.
Now, Belarus, you can say, is kind of a
quasi extension of Russia. Russia even
is said to have tactical nuclear
warheads on Belarus territory. So, and
and Ukraine could fall to Russia
depending on what Mr. Putin decides to
do with the war. So then what comes next
in line is Poland mainly. It's a big
bulvar. You also have small nations like
Slovakia and Hungary but the big one is
Poland. So Poland is now being
weaponized. They the west is now trying
to turn uh Poland into the next great
military power in Europe. And I think
the concess the concession they've given
to Poland for that for being the next in
line is that okay we'll we'll allow you
to not accept illegal immigrants. So
yeah, Shiva Rajput says, "Do we need a
farright right-wing political party?" I
think there's space for all kinds of
political parties in India. Uh I don't
think India has a single farright
political party. We only have centrist
political parties at best. It's not a
criticism. It's just an observation.
Okay. Uh so there's no harm in having a
more far-right political party to cater
for uh the political uh views of some
people who are not possibly being
represented at this point in time. We do
have far-left political parties in
India. I'll not name them, but we know
we know that they exist, but it looks
like we don't have a single farright
political party. So, what's the harm in
having a properly balanced political
spectrum? There's no harm in having
that. So, yeah, it's not a bad thing to
have. Uh, Vishal says, can you explain
how modern dictatorship will
be? What would a modern dictatorship
look like? It will look like it will
look like look I can give you three
examples. One is North Korea. North
Korea is a vasal of a bigger
dictatorship which is China. So North
Korea is a very is said to be a very
repressive nation. Just one family rules
the country. The grandfather used to
rule it. Then the the father used to
rule it. Now the son is ruling it. And
his family controls things. uh Kim
Jong-un's most trusted adviser is his
sister and his uncles and aunts and
other family members are part of the
inner circle. So it's a familyrun system
and their major their only patron is Mr.
Xiinping and they also have a an
alliance with Mr. Vladimir Putin and
it's said to be a very repressive
country in which no criticism of the
ruling elite is allowed and uh so on so
forth. So that's uh that's one model of
a dictatorship. Okay. Completely
militarized nation and so on. Um the
second model is China, a one party state
where there is some space for disscent
these days and disagreement. But overall
if you if you step too too far beyond
the gray line, the gray zone, then you
will be taken care of by the Chinese
Communist Party and there's no coming
back from that.
Um and yeah in in China you know there's
a great the great censorship wall the
great internet firewall and all that but
Chinese citizens do go outside the
country and study in the west and so on
do come back to China and there is still
patriotism in China and the social
contract in China is that we will remain
a one party system but the contra but in
exchange for that for you for the people
of China agreeing to having only one
party ruling the country as a
dictatorship in exchange for that we
will give you the best possible living
standards and we will make China a great
nation. That's the social contract. So
that's second model of dictatorship. The
third model of of dictatorship is a
hidden dictatorship. That's the United
States. It's a two-party system. Okay.
The other political parties that may
exist are irrelevant. It's a two-party
system. But both parties, the two
parties, the Democrats and the
Republicans have very different views on
domestic politics and governance. But
they have the same outlook when it comes
to geopolitics, when it comes to foreign
policy, when it comes to economic
policy.
externally and so
on. So it's essentially a monoparty
system, your one party system
masquerading as a two-party democracy.
And at the end of the day, it doesn't
matter who is the president of the US. I
mean, when you had Biden, we know
everyone knew that Biden wasn't running
the country and neither was Kamala
Harris mentally competent to run the
country. So somebody was running the
country from behind the scenes. So
that's the clear hallmark of a of a
hidden dictatorship. And right now Trump
is supposedly running the country. He's
upending the entire economic scene
globally. He's doing tremendous amounts
of damage and it looks like he has been
given that mandate by the by whoever
runs the country to do that otherwise he
won't be allowed to do it. So that's
that's the third model of what a
dictatorship would look like. You know a
dictatorship masquerading as a vibrant
democracy. So yeah that's three
different
models. Simply a says why Ambedkar fell
for my I have absolutely no idea sir
absolutely I have not studied Dr.
Rammedgar and I'm not going to take
questions about domestic politics like
I've clearly said in in the thing. So I
have no idea. No. Uh please compare
China versus India independence
movement. The Chinese independence
movement. Well it's the Chinese
independence movement was a civil war
between the the Kind Tang and and the
the Chinese Communist Party. The Indian
Indian independence movement was smashed
and destroyed in 1857.
The Indian let me repeat the Indian in
independence movement was smashed and
destroyed in 1857. After that there was
a fake independence movement which was
which was stage managed by the
British and at the end of the day in
1947 we were given a quasi independence.
It was a transfer of power from one set
to of one set of crooks to another set
of crooks. Their handpicked crooks were
given power and nothing changed in India
after independence. The same systems
continued in China everything changed.
So very different very different
tremendously different tremendously
different. Akshit Pande says can we
expect Nepal and Bhutan back in the
motherland? Listen imagine
Nepal becomes part of India then we will
apply Indian secularism on
Nepal. Do you want that to happen or
would you rather prefer Nepal to become
a Hindu raashtra again? I would prefer
Nepal to become a Hindu raashtra again
to have its monarchy
restored. If you give me the choice
Nepal becomes a monarchy and a Hindu
raashtra or Nepal becomes a part of bhat
India not bat. Right now India is not
bat India is India right now. I would
take monarchy I would take Nepal becomes
a monarchy and a Hindu raashtra and
remains independent from India with the
same uh you know understanding that we
have with open borders and all that. I
would prefer that right now than
imposing Indian the Indian version of
secularism on
Nepal. Bhutan also I don't want to see
Indian secularism imposed on on on
Bhutan. It's a toxic form of secularism.
The same goes for Sri
Lanka. Uh Ashra says how can India
benefit from the recent NATO increase in
military budget or big daddy US will not
allow any Indian companies to make any
deal with NATO countries. Look, NATO
countries can only buy US weapons.
Please understand this. It's the biggest
scam they have been running. You create
wars and all these tremendously
tremendous problems in the world and
then you sell weapons
everywhere. Why would NATO allow Indian
companies to sell weapons to NATO
countries? No, they can only buy
American weapons. They will never allow
Indian companies to make any deals with
NATO countries.
So, but India will is on track to become
a major defense exporter and we will
export to countries that are aligned
geopolitically with us. We'll sell to
Armenia. We may sell to Russia. We may
sell to all the Southeast Asian
nations. We will sell to African nations
if if required. We may sell to nations
in Latin America. We have tremendous
weapons. We have battle tested weapons.
weapons that have that have vested
American and Chinese systems. Okay. So,
India is on track to become a major
defense exporter but the NATO nations
will not benefit from that because the
US won't allow this to
happen. Kumar Patel says ECE CE
branch which branch is more AI proof for
the future? What is ECE? What is
C? Okay, I'll have to
um I'll have to Google this. I have no
idea what that is. and
uh not sure if it falls in a within
geopolitic history or science but let's
see ECE and C what is
that electrical look electrical and
computer engineering C listen I don't
have the answer to this question I don't
know I despise India's education system
I am not aware of the all the
complexities in the Indian education
system and all the different branches
that they have so I am the last person
who should be asking these questions I
am not the right person I Don't look
into all these things. I despise the
Indian education system which is rotten
to the core. So I'm sorry I don't have
the answer to your
question. Anonymous scientist says is
the US hiding outcomes of operation
sundial? Question mark.
Why? Okay. Another term which I am which
is not ringing a bell for me. What is
operation sundial? Operation sundial.
What is that?
Operation
Sundial. Operation Sundial. Sundial
weapon. One of two massive nuclear bombs
planned for testing etc. etc. It was
gigatons. 100 gigatons if built and
detonated. Look, as far as as we know,
the largest nuclear weapon that was that
has ever been detonated atmospherically
or anywhere else is the tar bomba which
had a 50 gigaton sorry 50 megaton yield.
The sund dial thing which says
gigaton clearly it's not been tested.
No, if it was tested then the world
would have known. So as far as I
understand no they're not hiding it. I
don't think it ever happened. a 100
gigaton bomb I
mean no matter where you are in the
world you'll
notice okay Jagan says
sir your opinion regarding stalling
agreement by India government will it
further complicate and compromise
national data security why did did Elon
buy mast and Donald Trump fool the
entire world with the fight okay you got
to take the the possibility very
seriously that maybe it's a fake fight
maybe it's a it's engineered fight to to
achieve certain outcomes. So fool the
world. Make the world believe that you
know Elon Musk and Donald Trump are
fighting. They don't get along with each
other and then pull what they what do
they call it? Uno reverse card or
something. Maybe it's a possibility. So
we have to be careful. Uh but maybe it's
a true fight. Maybe it's a real fight
and uh it's something that people could
have seen coming potentially. Uh what's
my opinion about stling? I've spoken
this spoken about this so many times. I
think it's a tremendously rotten
agreement. It's terrible for India's
national security. It's terrible for
India's sovereignty.
Why is it terrible for India
sovereignty? Imagine three scenarios.
One, terrorists in Kashmir. Second,
terrorists in the Mauist infested red
belt. Third, cookie terrorists in
Manipur. Okay. Now, let's say the the
the terrorists are doing whatever
terrorists do. So, you impose a internet
blackout for 48 hours so that they can't
communicate with each other. In the
meanwhile, you go and neutralize them.
But what if you impose an internet
blackout but Starling keeps on beaming
over there then the terrorists will be
able to coordinate with with each other
and do whatever they need to do and
evade the the law enforcement agencies
and whatever terrible for India
sovereignty. If you call up Elon Musk
and say switch off for 48 hours, he'll
say no, I won't do it. Then what will
you do? H or let's say in some part of
India in some city there's rioting. You
know there are people who tend to riot
for some reason in this country and for
that let's say you impose a 48 hour
blackout but Starling is coming. So what
do you do then? You are kind of losing
your sovereignty. I think it's a
tremendously bad agreement. I think we
should revoke the license that has
apparently been given and now is a good
time to revoke it when Elon Musk and
Trump are fighting. Revoke the license
and it's okay. We don't need your
goddamned Tesla uh gigaf factories or
whatever in India. We'll make our own
gigaf
factories. Okay, captain. Um whatever
that is, I mean what is stopping India
from raising Taiwan and Tibet? What is
stopping India from raising Taiwan? What
is the point of going blah blah with
words? The only things that matter in
geopolitics are
actions. What is the point of giving a
mut job verbally? This is what Indians
don't understand. because of this this
uh this this uh uh debate culture that
we have this debate culture in various
YouTubers in India huh they think that
by giving strong words and statements
you have defeated the enemy that's not
how it works that's not how it
works your your strong words are not
going to defeat the enemy it's going to
have no effect whatsoever it's going to
make you look like a fool so please
please grow up people please grow grow
up a little bit especially if you watch
this channel. Please grow up a little.
That's the overall objective of the
channel to help you grow a
little. Okay. LS, thank you so much sir.
You didn't ask a question but I really
appreciate uh the contribution. Thank
you sir or ma'am whatever you are. AJ
Sharma says did I decode it promote
veganism or veg at the same time
destroying Indian food image? by just
peasants stay on their processed meat. I
mean, what are you referring to, sir?
Did you decode what
exactly? You're talking about that
cockroach milk thing. I'm not sure.
Um, promote veganism or veg same time
destroying Indian. I'm I'm a little
confused. I'm not sure what the question
is and what what are you referring to?
who is trying are you talking about some
specific country or some specific
organization or some specific group of
people it helps if you give a little bit
more context otherwise I'm not able to
understand Bres welcome and thank you
very much um captain etc by the way you
look like an asimist priest with this
hairstyle well thank you
uh please uh what just look and search
the monk who is saving Mao Majoli from
Christian proletizer Swaja. Well, let's
check it out, shall we? Let's check it
out. Um um um um let's put that on the
screen. Let's do a Google search. Okay.
The monk the monk who is
uh
savingly from
etc. The monk who is saving
Majoli. Okay, that's not my hairstyle at
all, but okay, I get what you
mean. Not sure that's my hairstyle. Do
you see
this? See that? That's not my hairstyle.
Anyhow, thank you.
Um,
estral
it's it's not often that I'm speechless,
isn't it? Okay, let me try and decode
this long-term effect of indie plate
with
yup with Eurasian
plate
to
Japan Bangladesh Japan. Okay. Long-term
effects of effect of Indian plate
smashing into the Eurasian plate. Higher
Himalayas, higher and higher, higher and
higher eventually. Okay. Second,
Bangladesh, Japan. I I hear that Japan
the government of Japan is is going to
accept a 100,000
Bangladeshes workers because they have a
shortage of workers. Are are you people
crazy? They will never return. They are
this is the beginning of the end of
Japan if if you if you have such
policies.
Bangladeshies, my god. Don't you know
what Bangladeshies do in
India?
Ah.
Ah. Horrible. Hurts me to see this. I'm
not Japanese. Oh
god. Okay.
Prelt. How did Italian bankers survive
all collapses and go global while other
bankers
perished? Why Freemasons became so
powerful across the world? Once again,
this is what you call conspiracy
theories. Show me one powerful
Freemason. Okay, let's let's Google
powerful
Freemasons. See, I'm not saying that
these are what you're saying is fake,
but there's no way of proving it. Okay,
let's see. Powerful Freemasons. Who are
the who are powerful freemasons?
Okay.
Um let's see. George Washington was
apparently Freemason. Franklin
Roosevelt, Harry Truman was a freemason.
Winston Churchill, Simon Bullivar,
Douglas MacArthur, Mozart, Buzz Aldrin,
Benjamin Franklin, Mark Twain, Alexander
Fleming, etc. Oscar Wild. Well, Oscar
Wild was very badly intreated by the
British. Natkin Cole, okay. Freemason
uh famous okay powerful Indian
freemasons let's see very strange names
will come in okay I promise you that
okay grand lodge of Bombay come on open
up bro why are these websites so slow so
let's read about famous Indian
freemasons firos shame navi swami
vive pandit gi mutil gi nehuji president
fakrudin etc whatever the name Sir Dab
Jamat Gulas Narat Mur Ibraim Karim Boy
BGI Dr. Chakraarti Raj
Gopalachari Sir CP Ramas Swami IRC
Junjit Si J Boy sir Mult Sultan Muhammad
Shah
Aakhano Maraj Dulip Singh Nab sir Amin
jung whatever that is David Abraham
never heard of it him Ras Maflal justice
maiden Dr. Firo Setna GL Raha Narayan
Maharaja Jay Chamar Via Wow H
Martandanda his holiness whatever that
is a Khan okay the Nab of Pati Mansurali
Khan um Maharaja of Cindy well that's
interesting so some fascinating names
for Viveanandanda Motilal Ghuji and so
many other interesting names so you have
famous freemason who some of them seem
to be pretty
powerful. Why did they become powerful?
Look, if you have a coordinated
organization with lots of connections
and powerful people who are willing to
help each other, etc. and willing to,
you know, open various doors, it makes
you powerful. It makes you powerful. And
if it's a global organization, it makes
you even more powerful. So that's how it
works. Italian bankers survive
collapses. I'm not sure about the
Italian bankers angle. Uh how many big
Italian banks do we have today? I think
most of the big banks are based in
London or or the
US. Uh Udai Kumar says will we ever see
US fall in India rise as a hyperpower if
India accepts proposal of brick currency
and its GDP reaches a significant size 8
trillion by 2029 to avoid Chinese yuan
getting unfair age over Indian rupee
world. Will we ever see the US fall?
Look, every single empire that we know
of in history has
fallen. So obviously the US empire that
currently is the hyperpower will fall
one day. Now how and when is a qu it's
an open question and I'm not going to
venture a guess as to how it will happen
or when it will happen. Right now it is
at the peak of its
power. Eventually someday it will fall.
No question about it. That is
guaranteed. I give you there's a 100%
probability it will happen. What time
period? I don't know. I'll not venture a
guess. Okay. So will India rise as a
hyperpower? Well, that's a bigger
question. There's a lower probability of
that happening because for that India
will have to change fundamentally. India
will have to become an imperial-minded
country which means it has to go away
from it has to move away from being from
being a democracy to being more of a
monarchy imperial system like we had
historically. But lots of people will
moan if this happens and whine and
complaint if this happens. Oh, democracy
is
best,
right? And of course there's a there's a
danger when it comes to monarchies
because if you're a bad monarch then
democracy is looks like the nicest thing
in the world and so on. If India accepts
the proposal of breaks, India is not
accepting that that proposal because
once you become part of a of a of a
combined currency in which a more
powerful nation controls things and it's
over for you not going to
happen the bricks currency will become a
proxy for the yuan then just like the
euro is a proxy for the Deutsch mark. So
not going to happen.
Nanda Kishor says every country is in
debt but to who? Well, that's a good
question. To who? Right. Yeah, that
that's the big question in economics but
even I can't answer that
question. Um ICBM said says at
Sanders view is India Navy vast vastly
underrated. Well, we haven't seen the
Indian Navy in action for a long time. I
think Indian N the Indian Navy could
could really really surprise a lot of
people. So yeah, I think the people who
underrate the Indian Navy is vastly
underrated. I mean, I would have loved
to see the Indian Navy in action during
the operation Synindhur. I'm not sure
what this at Sanders thing is, but I
would have loved to see the Indian Navy
in operation in in action operation.
Maybe in action against the uh
terrorists in Karachi. I mean there are
there are known terrorists who are said
to have residences in Karachi and so on.
So there could have been potentially
some action there. So I think the Indian
Navy itself is very powerful and very
very
underrated. Sadesh's financial
consultancy follow up to the Nagalan
question. Okay. Shouldn't we try to
bring the far east back to the
indigenous culture as it will be better
for the long-term stability of India
especially with the US trying to carve
out a new new nation? Oh yes,
absolutely. We should try and bring our
far east back to their indigenous
culture. It's obviously going to be
better for India's long-term security,
stability, cultural integrity,
civilizational
integrity, overall integration of all
people. It'll be great. And yeah, I know
what you're mentioning over here. The
project K cookie land for Christ. The US
is trying to create an artificial cookie
country, cookie land for Christ out of
parts of Manipur, parts of maybe the
whole of Mizoram, maybe some parts of
Bangladesh, some and some parts of
Myanmar.
This is this is a project that the
Americans started during the Biden
regime. I'm not sure if the Trump regime
has entirely rolled it back or even
started rolling it back. So I think it's
still a problem. The cookie terrorism is
still a problem in Manipur. It's going
to be a long-standing
problem. So India needs to bring the Far
East back to their indigenous culture.
It's going to be a long process because
the the the destruction of the culture
and replacing with the foreign culture
took decades but it needs to happen. The
first thing you need to do is to stop
the funding for all these foreign
organizations that have infiltrated the
place. Foreign religious organizations
that essentially rule the place. It
needs to happen. So I completely agree
with you sir. Mystic SK says what
options other than military and
diplomatic power can India develop to
fight against the threats as China and
others want hesitate to use bioweapons?
It's not our dharm to do the same.
Okay, let's not discuss bioweapons and
whether it is our dharma to do the same
or not. Listen, the our dharma is to
safeguard our population and ensure our
victory. Our if you are the leader of
India, the prime minister, you have a
very simple, very clear
dharma. Ensure the long-term security,
prosperity and success of the nation and
the people. long term, not today, not 5
minutes, not not two weeks, long term.
I'm talking about 200 years
minimum. And whatever you need to do to
achieve that, it's fine to do it. If if
if something is worth fighting for, it
is worth fighting dirty for. That's what
I would
say. Some people will cry about this.
They'll say, "You're very bad." Okay,
I'm very
bad. But that's how it is. Leading a
nation, leading a civilization is not
for children. It's not for amateurs.
Only a few can do it. And even many
people who have led this country have
messed up so
badly. Uh so yeah, these are the
options. So I think that answer that I
just gave you, I think it answers your
question. Everything is on the table as
long as it serves the national interest.
Don't impose restrictions on your
actions es especially when it comes to
the to to serving the national interest
the civilizational interest that's what
I would say if others will do it why
can't we do it we know others will do it
whatever it is
hypothetically we should have the
answers to all uh questions that they
pose to
us okay wtiag thank you sir the
US. Okay, I'm glad you you opened this
up. Thank you, sir. I'm glad you opened
this up. The US had huge presence at the
Nurh Khan air base to target
Afghanistan. Well, to target whatever.
And even the Pakistanis did not know
what kind of weapons they brought. Do
you think they're hiding nukes there?
It's a perfect location to tackle Iran
and China. Map. Well, let's see the map.
Okay, Glad is prompting me. Map. Map.
Hello.
Let's let's do that. This is a very very
interesting topic now. It's all coming
out now what the Americans are up to. So
Nur Khan Air Base, Nur
Khan Khan Air Base, Chakala Laala,
whatever that means. Chakla
Laala. Nur Khan Air Base. Where's the
thing? Here it is. Shoe Baktar Cricket
Ground. Okay. This is the Okay. This is
the satellite imagery of the Nurh Khan
Air Base. Now let's let's see if we can
see any aircrafts over here. These are
clearly
uh aircrafts that are of American
origin. Let's zoom in further. Let's
zoom in further. What do we see? They
may Do they have Pakistani markings or
what markings do they have? I'm not sure
it's very clear. I can't see from here.
What sort of markings do they
have? Uh what is this thing
here? Could be a Pakistani markings but
that doesn't prove or disprove
anything. These seem to be of American
origin the manufacturer. I mean okay you
can even see human beings here.
Pakistani human
beings and uh what do we have here? So I
I I notice a lack of fighter aircraft
but these are all military aircraft of
various kinds. What kind of hanggars do
we have? where you can hide stuff. Well,
you have
hangars. Okay, we have some hangars. We
can't see what's inside, obviously.
That's why hangars exist. We have an we
have a hangar
here. And do we have those rapid
deployment things? Not quite. So, this
is not for fighter planes, it looks
like, cuz otherwise you would have those
rapid deployment uh runways where you
can, you know, very quickly. Okay, we
have some of that here. Okay. Okay. So
maybe they have fighter jets in here
which can be rapidly
deployed on demand at at maybe 5 minutes
notice. So this is Nurhan air base and
from the news that is emerging okay from
the news that is
emerging it looks like this air base was
off limits to Pakistani military
personnel which means that it was
apparently being operated by the
Americans.
Uh-huh. And they had never told us about
this. So, we smashed that air base and
it looks like there were some well,
there was some damage of some kind. And
maybe it's that that triggered America's
panic response that you got to stop
this. So, we don't know what what kind
of weapons are there, what they are
targeting. I don't know
who who they are targeting.
I mean Afghanistan is under
control. Iran there are well Pakistan is
a good place to keep an eye on Iran from
and let's see how far this air base is
from Iran. Let's let's quickly take a
look. So how far is it from the Avdan
border? How far is it from Iran? How far
is it from any other country? Well, by
the way, okay, let's see how far it is
from from Afghanistan.
The shortest distance is about 190
something kilometers. How far is it from
Shrinagar?
Huh? From Shinagar it is. It is 160 km
from Sinagar. How far is it from
Delhi? It is 670 km from Delhi. How far
from
Kabul? Uh 375 km. And when it comes to
Iran, I mean it doesn't make any sense.
If you want to have if you want to keep
an eye on Iran, you would do quitta. You
would definitely not do an air base in
Punjab. Okay? So let's not even discuss
the Iran matter from here over here.
It's a good place from where you can
keep an eye on India very much. The
Kashmir situation, the Kashmir area, the
Ladak area, uh the various air bases we
have, uh the Pakistan facing air bases
that we have in the western se sector of
India. If you if you have uh certain
kinds of assets in the Nuran base, you
can keep an eye on what's happening in
the New Delhi region, right? And yeah,
you can also access Afghanistan pretty
easily over here. And if you have good
enough instruments, etc., you can even
keep an eye on Tibet, occupied Tibet,
occupied Shinjang, etc. But the
proximity and location of this air base
tells me it was meant for keeping an eye
on
India. Okay, that's how I see it.
So it's not a perfect location to tackle
Iran or China. It's the right location
to tackle
India. So the Americans apparently were
operating the Nurhan air base.
H they have never told us about this.
That makes us that that makes me
question everything the Americans are
doing. Are they really India's friends
and allies like they claim? Are the
Pakistani nuclear weapons really
Pakistani? I don't think so at all
anymore. I don't think the Pakistanis
have the brains to develop nuclear
weapons. I don't think the Pakistanis
have the brains. They may have the same
DNA as us, but they don't have the
brains. Something has gone wrong that
has, you know, meddled up their
DNA. So I think the Pakistani nuclear
weapons are actually US nuclear weapons
deployed against us.
So that tells you the relationship that
we have with the US or rather the the
that tells you how the Americans regard
us as
enemies. I am pretty pretty
much beginning to think that the
Pakistani nuclear weapons are US nuclear
weapons. Vidi says is there any other
truth behind 911 US is too powerful? I
don't
know. Clearly there there could be
something beyond what we know.
be maybe it was not Osama, maybe it was
somebody else. Uh maybe there is some
cover up but what it what is it? I have
no
idea. Dian Chunan says, "Is China really
that strong or is it just propaganda?
Their weapons failed in operation zindor
and with total censorship nobody knows
their real weaknesses. Could India
actually win a war against
them?" Well, the truth lies somewhere in
between most likely.
uh their weapons the ones they had
supplied to Pakistan they obviously
failed but then Pakist then the Chinese
because of this they got good realtime
data battle battle data and I'm sure
that the weapons they had supplied to
Pakistan were not their best weapons or
even if they were now they'll be able to
improve them right and uh so that's one
that's one point um and operation
synindur was simply an air war a
three-day war it was brought to an end
premature ly or don't pause prematurely.
Uh the fact that the Chinese have
censorship total censorship that is a
strength as well as a weakness. So maybe
they have something to
hide that that's what it could mean and
maybe it's also a strength because the
outside world cannot really know what's
happening within
China. Uh the last question is do you
think India could actually win a war
against them? Well, it depends on what
kind of war it is. If it's a border war,
a Himalayan war, I think in which, you
know, technology
um cannot play that big a role because
of the incredibly difficult
terrain. Uh so tanks, you can have light
tanks at best. I've seen those light
tanks. They're pretty light actually
compared to the big big heavy tanks, the
battle tanks that you typically have. I
have seen tanks on the roads on the on
the on the
extremely treacherous roads of Ladak.
So maybe you could have light tanks and
maybe you could have those attack
helicopters. Ours are better than the
the Chinese attack helicopters and so
on. So I think if it's a limited uh
border war I think India would seriously
pose a challenge to China. I think we
have tremendous missiles. I think we may
have the deadliest missiles in the world
and the Tibetan airfields and and Pak
and and Chinese bases are sitting ducks.
They can reinforce those things but we
can do hit after hit and just you know
punch a hole into their
defenses. The question is how many
missiles do we have? What's our
stockpile like? We need to have a
stockpile of tens of thousands of
missiles of various kinds. Has the
government ensured that we have such a
stockpile? If we have a stockpile of
tens of thousands of missiles is you
know a war with India for China will be
a huge mistake. But we if we haven't
done our homework and if we don't have
sufficient quantities of missiles etc
then it then the longer a war goes on
the more dangerous it will become for
India to win to to yeah to win or to it
could it will mean that we we could
possibly end up losing because of a
shortfall of weapons. So the most
important thing in today's day and age
is you need to have stockpiles
significant stockpiles of of kami Khaz
drones of anti- uh aircraft and anti-
drone systems you know uh defensive
uh defensive uh infrastructure defensive
weapons. You need to have stockpiles of
long, medium etc range missiles, cruise
missiles, ballistic missiles and so on
and so forth. So all of that needs to be
there. We have to be prepared for this
to happen at a moment's notice
essentially right don't uh start taking
action after the threat threat becomes
real and shows you shows its face we
know the threat already exists so I
think India can win a war against China
and India can humble China tremendously
maybe even make their hold on Tibet uh
kind of uh shaky or weak if we plan
properly for all contingencies right
now MNSH says if the Brahos missile
misfire was seen as a way to test
Pakistan's air defense capabilities.
Could operation Synindur be a India's
attempt to test its nuclear capabilities
as
well? Maybe. Maybe. Look, we don't have
clear evidence this way or that way. Was
the was it a really a misfire that
Brahmos missile thing that happened like
two three years
ago or was it a test a way to test
Pakistan's air
defenses because the the missile nobody
the Pakistanis did not even attempt to
intercept the missile. It just flew into
Pakistan and hit some some some kind of
target. Um so it was clearly a brahmos
missile that ended up in Pakistan and
the Pakistanis did not take any action
to stop it probably because it was not
going towards any sensitive location in
Pakistan you know one of their military
bases or terrorist bases it just went
and hit some some random location um so
maybe it was a way of gouging what kind
of response Pakistan will even when this
sort of thing happens uh is sindur
India's attempt to Pakist Pakistan's
nucle capabilities as
Maybe in a way it was because a lot has
become clear after this that Pakistan's
nuclear blackmail is bluff. I mean the
bluff was called and and that blackmail
is has fallen flat. No matter how much
we hit Pakistan, how hard we behave we
hit Pakistan. The best they did was to
go crying to the
Americans. They did not even make a
single threat of using nuclear weapons.
They went to the Americans and and
begged the Americans to intervene. And
especially when we hit 11 air bases in
20 minutes including Nurh Khan which is
owned by the Americans. That's when the
Americans made a stop. They asked us to
stop. So Pakistan did not come even
close to to considering nuclear weapons.
And that makes me wonder are those
nuclear weapons really Pakistani
weapons. I am now of the opinion that
these are American weapons and the big
red button lies in the hands of America
not Pakistan.
So I think that has become rather clear
after operation sindur which
completely reshapes the India US
relationship. It's good to know who
really stands with us and who really are
our
enemies. Nishant Khalita says did bat
fail to modernize and innovate our
military weapon systems after a certain
time in ancient times which led to
losses during the medieval Islamic
invasions. Kindly give specific
examples.
The reason we
lost the reason we were we we first lost
Gandhar and then slowly over a few
centuries we lost more territory. The
reason is not because we once had
superior military weapons and then we
did not modernize. That is not the
reason. The reason was that we did not
have political unity in
Bat. If these invasions had been
attempted during the Kushan era when the
great Shri Kaneshka was our emperor,
those invasions would have been smashed
like you would smash a cockroach or a
mosquito. If the invasion had happened
during the time of Shri Ashok, the same
thing would have happened. He would have
been super cruel to those invaders. If
this is this had happened during the
time of Kumar Gupta or Chandra
Gupta of the Gupta Empire or Scanda
Gupta or Samudra Gupta they would have
been smashed to bits no matter what
weapon systems they had. The reason we
fell to the invasions eventually was
because of lack of political unity
because during the Kushan era, during
the Moria era, during the Gupta era, we
had one emperor ruling over entire
paratwash. But during the time when the
the Turk and Arabic invasions happened,
we had a lack of political community. We
did not have a single empire. We had
lots of different
kingdoms and each kingdom acted
independently of each other. They had
their own petty jealousies and
rivalries. And because they did not
fight together as one entity that's why
the invaders were able to defeat one at
a time and eventually they were able to
take over the subcontinent started with
Gandhar. Gandhar was this beautiful
place seat of ancient culture and wisdom
seat of learning in universities.
Gandhar it was the original
Kashmir. So those are the specific
examples I can give you. It has nothing
to do with military weapons systems etc.
Anonymous says, "How can a person become
self-employed? Find develop some skills
that can help you provide some kind of
genuine value to
society. Find out whatever the skills
are. I mean, it depends on what you're
good at, what your aptitudes are. So
acquire some skills that can help you
provide genuine value to society. Value
that society really needs. So let's say
there are some problems in society.
Every society has problems. Every so
society has a certain population whose
needs are not being
served. Find a way to serve those needs
and then charge for the value you're
providing. That's how you become
self-employed.
Sir Sid says, "Your views on the recent
fight between Musk and Trump. Musk made
a serious allegation regarding the
Epstein files. Friendship did not last
even a year. Crazy, you know." Yeah. So
Elon Musk made this very serious
allegation that the reason why Cash
Patel, the director of the FBI, is not
releasing the Epstein files, it's been
so so many days is because Donald Trump
figures features on the Epstein files.
So So Musk made this allegation on
Twitter and now he has deleted the
tweets. Okay, he knows everybody has
taken screenshots. He knows that. But
now he has deleted the tweet. So it's
like, oh, I'm retracting my allegation
now. So my question is, is Musk himself
a liar? Can he be trusted? The second
question is, if he knew all along that
Trump features on the Epstein files,
then why didn't he why didn't Elon Musk
put put this out in the public domain
immediately? I mean, don't you have
don't you know that there's something
called principles? If somebody is, let's
say, if you feature on the Epstein
files, it means you you are a
you you you you are essentially a
pedophile or something like that,
right? So if you know that somebody is
that sort of person, you were okay to
work with him and say that you love the
guy as long as he gave you what you
wanted. And then now that he is Trump
has pushed pushed uh Musk out of his
cabinet and out of the White House, now
Musk is happy to uh you know come up
with with the truth. What kind of person
is this? a self-serving person, a person
who lacks
principles. So it looks like both these
people, both these individuals lack
principles. That's what it looks like to
me. Trump is also that sort of person. I
have seen this over a very long period
of time. Uh he Trump will say
whatever is required to get what he
wants. It doesn't have to be the truth.
He will say one thing one day, he will
say the opposite the next day with a
completely straight face. That has been
Trump's modest operandi and he boasts
about that in his book the art of the
deal. So he's not a trustworthy person.
Maybe his principle is that I going to
make money. That's the
principle. But there are deeper
principles beyond that. Right? So it
looks like no it doesn't look like it's
clear that both of these gentlemen uh
they lack integrity. uh they are not
trustworthy people and they're the last
people who should be ruling the
world. Uh so so Trump is going to be
around for another three and a half
years. After that he's gone. He's done
done and dusted. But Musk is going to be
around for
longer. So it's not a friendship. It's a
it was an alliance of convenience. Musk
once tweeted that I love Donald Trump as
much as the man can love another man.
That sort of tweet he made and see now.
So yeah, that's that's just how it is.
You can't trust these people. not
trustworthy. Uh Vamshi Khalim says 1857
wasn't Indian movement Muslims tried
Mughal restoration. There were other
people also fought in this h it was not
just Muslims fighting to restore uh the
Mughal
rule. The all it started by the way not
from a Mughal or Muslim thing. It
started from uh merit with Mongal Pande
and then it just snowballed and spread
like a firestorm everywhere. So this is
a this is a complicated thing. There are
layers to this but you can't you know
pigeon hole this into a mughal
restoration in one sentence. It's way
more complicated than that. Sumi says
should India form a NATO alliance with
Russia against the deep
state.
Yeah I'm I'm sure it sounds very good as
an idea but the world doesn't work like
that. It doesn't work like that. It
won't happen.
XPG0007 says respect from Punjab respect
back sir thank you so much what will the
geopolitical impact of accepting SU57
offer with full tech and code transfer
with the current India US relationship
the Americans will throw a tantrum
tantrum tantrum they'll say how dare you
do such a thing how dare you yeah but
we'll say come on you people are
operating in Pakistan h you have given
Pakistan your nuclear weapons and you
want us to do whatever you guys say
despite you acting as our enemies. Your
actions are those of enemies. Your words
are those of friends, but your actions
matter more than words. Uh and if you if
you buy your your trash can, the the
F-35, it'll cost 110 mill 10 million per
piece and you're going to force us to to
ask for an OTP every morning before we
take out take it out to fly. And before
we get the OTP, we have to give the
entire flight plan. And even then, even
even if we agree to all this, if you
want to bomb the Durhan Airbase using
your F-35, we will switch off the thing.
You won't allow us to bomb it. So why
should we buy your overpriced piece of
garbage? So the thing is it will cause a
deterioration in India US
relationship. But we have no choice. We
cannot buy the F-35. And the Americans
aren't their actions aren't those of
friends. Their actions are those of an
enemy
nation. Uh Shubam says how to learn new
things. What's your way please guide? I
don't know. I just do it automatically
subconsciously. I just I just learn uh I
I see if it's if it's knowledge. Let's
say I want to learn a piece of history.
For example, I have never really read
about the Maratas Empire. Okay, I know
about it obviously as as I've read about
it as part of other historical contexts,
but I've never really read about the
Marat Empire. What would I do? I would
buy the five top top rated books about
Marata history and I'll read them all
multiple times. At least I'll remember
some of it. Then whatever I found
interesting, I will go I'll do deep
dives on the on that based on the
internet and based on every other thing.
So I'll spend a month or so doing this.
It takes time. Takes time. I read super
fast. I read at light speed. It'll still
take me maybe a month. After a month,
I'll feel that I'm reasonably
comfortable that I have some
understanding of marat history. Then
I'll continue the research phase going
deeper deeper into rabbit holes over
specific topics. And this this period of
time may take me a year or two. That's
how I learn, right? That's how you
that's how you learn new things. It
takes time. You have to be committed and
you have to be really serious about
this. Uh if I want to learn, let's say
let's say I want to revisit tensor
calculus. Okay, it's been a while since
I used tensor. So maybe I must state
that I I remember so what would I do? I
remember how I learned tensor tensor
calculus which is which is a which is
math. How did I learn tensor calculus
the first time? I think it was during
the first year of college. I had a book
which is somewhere here. Sham series
tensor. No it was the sham series book
on vector calculus on vectors but it had
one chapter at the end on tensors.
So I just solved every single problem on
tensors that take me that took I would
do that after coming back home from
college in the evening. So every every
day after college for 2 three hours I
would solve the problems and I think it
took me three or four days if I if I
recall correctly after that I in that
time I was done with all the problems.
Then I acquired the Shom series book on
tensor calculus itself and that would
have taken me a couple of months but I
just ran through the whole book solved
every problem and by that if you do that
you're going to have a reasonably good
understanding of tensors and you can
then you can read general relativity
books and research papers. So that's how
you do it. It takes a tremendous amount
of time and effort and mental what would
you say will willpower but if you are
curious if you want to learn stuff it's
it's not something that's that's that's
uh that's a problem it's fun so that's
how I do
it Dr. Dester sirter says I think you've
made an error in the
g okay sir I made an error you are right
I'm wrong you're great sir okay thank
you gro says do you think without
foreign invasion bat could have become a
country and all princely states would
have agreed on a single king forever
there is nothing forever nothing is
forever do you think without foreign
invasion Bat would have been a
country without foreign invasion. We
would not have had princely states.
First of all, please understand what are
these princely states? The princely
states were the puppet regimes that were
put in power by the British after
killing all the real kings in
1857. In 1857, our real kings stood up
and fought the British. And the British
for whatever reason they were able to
succeed and they killed all the royal
families. They killed them physically
off with their heads or hang them. One
example is Rani Lakmibai and so on. They
killed everybody. And then what did did
they
do of whichever king or queen they had
killed? They would find some distant
distantly related family member. Okay.
And they would take some young kid from
that family and put that king as kid as
the next king. And then they would
educate that kid and completely
anglicize that kid. And these puppet
rulers became the rulers of the so and
then all these little kingdoms were
called princely states. And all these
little kings and queens they were
puppets of the
British. I think you will know their
names today.
And those were the princely states.
Before 1857, you had real
kingdoms and the British destroyed that.
So today, if somebody claims to be from
some royal family of some princely
states, they are descendants of puppets
who collaborated with the British. They
are not the true
uh descendants of the true kings of
India. Those are somewhere else. They
I'm sure they exist. I'm sure they
exist. But uh they are no longer
recognized and they are no longer know
known. And the ones who go around saying
oh we are descendants of princess
princely the rulers of princely states
those are the descendants of puppets and
collaborators without foreign
invasion. Yeah. So that's what I'll say
about this. Yeah. Dirj Kamat says
mainstream modern mainstream Dharmic
schools almost all promote passiveness
vegetarianism and suicidal tolerance
antiga trait traits which are causing
our population to disappear is this
design design funded by the west much of
it is funded by the west that's what I
will say without going into details and
naming
specifics many of these so-called
dharmic movements have been infiltrated
long ago
Many of these so-called dharmic
movements were taken over in the last
century in the 20th century. I am not
mentioning anybody. So don't throw a
tantrum those who are listening. I am
not specifically naming anyone. I'm not
saying every all of them are are
infiltrated. I am not saying every
dharmic movement is infiltrated but some
are without naming anyone.
So yeah, many of them promote these
things. Passiveness, vegetarianism, it's
a personal choice, but it's it's for the
person to
decide. Tolerance and so on. Anti- Gita
traits. Yeah, that's that's a great way
of putting it. Traits that are anti-
Gita, anti-hagat Gita, right? I mean,
the Bhagwat Gita is the is the
core of of what you got to learn as a
Hindu. Of course, we have so many other
texts which go all the way back to the
rigveda. But if you want to learn how to
live a great life and to be a great
person then there's no better text than
than than the than what Sri Krishna said
on the battlefield to Arjun when Arjuna
was wavering. Right? So anybody who
teaches you something that goes against
the Bhagat Gita, you've got to put a
huge question mark on that person's face
that who does this person really serve
and what is this person's real agenda?
That's all I will say about this. So
Dharma, thank you so much for bringing
this this to everybody's notice. Uh
unless somebody asks me a question, I
don't take these things. So you have
made me take this up. So I will say
this, I am not naming anybody. I am not
claiming that every dharmic school has
been taken over by the west. Not all but
some are. So how do you know that one of
that so and so dharmic school is
compromised if they are preaching
something that goes against the the the
original teachings of the of the Gita
the Bhagat
Gita. It is possible that some of these
dharmic schools may put out their own
versions of the Bhagwat Gita potentially
possibly. I'm not naming anybody but
once once
again it's also possible that these new
versions of the Bhagat Gita may have
some certain certain changes from what
Sri Krishna said and it's very difficult
for the ordinary person to find out what
these changes are and to even notice
that they have edited and modified this
thing
right and some of them insult other
Hindu gods and so on so I would say it's
it's a very dangerous thing it's a very
dangerous thing and it it's very
important for people to notice this and
realize that not all is
well. Shiva Rajput says could can the
new cold war between the US and China
turn into a real war and will Pakistan
be the battleground or the pawn role of
Pakistan China versus US? Pakistan is
there for India. Pakistan is a
pawn. It's always been a pawn and the
objective has always been to target
India. It's nothing to do with China. So
China wants to use Pakistan as a pawn to
target India. The US has always used
Pakistan as a pawn to target India.
Always. Of course for a decade or so
there was the focus on Afghanistan but
after that the focus came back to India.
Um so Pakistan has always been a po
pawn. It's not a battleground. It's an
expendable pawn. It's a disposable pawn.
Um can the new cold war turn into a real
war? I think both nations will try their
best not to have a real war because it
will be tremendously uh damaging to both
countries and their infrastructure and
their economies. The objective will be
to win without actually fighting
fighting a kinetic war. So hopefully it
doesn't turn into a real war because
then other nations will will get dragged
into it which is bad for everybody.
Regamy says prospects of self-reliance
defense wise. I think we are on a very u
good footing when it comes to
self-reliance defense wise.
Um uh look we we are completely
self-reliant when it comes to missiles
of every kind whether it's uh ballistic
missiles. We have short, medium, long,
intercontinental range ballistic
missiles. Okay, we have ballistic
missiles and possibly other missiles
with MIRV capability. Uh we have cruise
missiles of various ranges including
supersonic cruise missiles like the
Brahmos. We will eventually soon have
hypersonic cruise missiles. Uh we have
subsonic cruise missiles also which have
been pretty well tested and which could
be inducted. Uh we have various kinds of
drones very high quality
drones. So in in in these matters we are
extremely uh extremely uh very
self-sufficient in terms of these
things. Um when it comes to uh naval
stuff uh once again we have very good
missiles etc. Um we definitely can use
more submarines. One of the Achilles
heels that we have is submarines. Uh
whether it's nuclear, whether it's
conventional. So we need to have I would
in my opinion at least 50 submarines.
Come
on. If you have 50 submarines then it
means that any given at any given point
in time you may have 17 or so deployed
uh
operationally. How do I know that? well
secrets. Uh then air force wise the one
achilles heel there is is uh the jet
engine technology. So that's something
we need to figure out. So overall we are
on on on a very good track. There are
certain things that we need to figure
out. I think in 5 10 years we could be
one of the biggest defense exporters and
probably by the time if we can figure
out those couple of things. I'm sure
there's something some some other things
as well but those couple of things if if
you can figure out the jet engine and
the submarine thing then we could be a
tremendously powerful
nation. Um J Singh says is India's cold
start doctrine still valid? It could
still be valid for sure but maybe it's
evolved and we are not aware of it. See
India doesn't publicize and publish its
doctrine like some other nations do like
the US. Okay. So doctrines evolve after
operation Sindur. I promise you there's
been a lot of evolution in the doctrine.
Uh so maybe there's a new version of
cool start. Maybe cold start isn't trash
bin and we have a different kind of
doctrine possibly. Yeah. Maybe a pulse
pause war doctrine which is kind of cold
start but maybe different kind of cold
start. So it's hard to say. I'm uh what
I can tell you is that I it's it's a
given. It's almost a guarantee that
after operation Synindhur and all the
data that we all the data all the
observations all the feedback feedback
that came to us from our operations from
all the observational evidence we have a
lot will have changed in India's
doctrine we have way more intelligence
now way more intel we have now about the
way Pakistan's military operates what
their strengths are what their
weaknesses are what the other nations
involvement is and so on and that will
have helped us reshape our doctrine and
make it more more robust so I'm sure The
doctrine has
changed. DV Chandan Malik says, "Why
does Indian media focus on trials over
truth trials over truth? Despite 1.48
lakh outlets, none frame India's global
view. Is it slow courts or societal
stigma? Why is business failure seen as
crime? You've asked like multiple
questions, sir. Why does Indian media
focus on trials over truth? I'm not sure
what that means. Trials over truth.
Okay, I'm not able to understand that.
But yeah, despite 1.48 uh lakh outlets,
none frame India's global view. That's a
problem. That's a problem. I have been
saying this for the past four plus years
that why don't we have our own version
of of the BBC or the CNN or the Chinese
uh CC CCTN or whatever it is they call
it or Al Jazzer. All these little
nations have these mega outlets. the the
Germans have Deutsche Lady DW uh and so
on and so forth. The Chinese have the
thing. The Japanese have the thing. We
have
nothing. We have some of these channels
that have this 8:00 p.m. 9:00 p.m.
debates shouting matches with like six
to 8 to 12 people on the screen all
shouting at the same time. Nothing ever
emerges as an outcome of these debates.
I personally have been guilty of go of
going on these debates. I am still
invited to these debates. Um but what's
the outcome and how does it set our
agenda globally? It doesn't. It
essentially turns us into a laughing
stock. You know the west kind of makes
fun of India like you have 28 different
people on the screen and all these
things going on and so on so forth. Uh
so that's a problem. We need to have a
very serious media outlet and the
government has Dur Dashan. Why can't we
transform Dudashan into a global beast?
I know Dudashan is still seen as this
1980s quality TV channel with completely
unprofessional uh staff and all that you
know
amateurs but you could completely revamp
them revamp the whole thing. The
government has the money more the
government has deeper pockets than
anybody else on on the in the country.
they can transform dud dash into a
global behemoth as India's mouthpiece as
India's you know the the the news outlet
that puts India's uh perspective up
front in front of the world which it
needs to happen but the doesn't look
like there is any um desire for this to
happen from the perspective of the
government so it is um sad to see uh
slow quotes I am not I I don't have any
idea what that Think you're mixing
questions over here. Why is business
failure seen as crime over
here? Business is seen as a crime in
India. If somebody makes money that it's
seen as a crime in India, right? If
somebody earns a little bit of money,
people start complaining. Haven't you
seen that? You see that all the time? I
turned on uh super chats recently
because I want to test it out and I want
to see uh whether the quality of the
questions improves and I get a 100 plus
complaints that you are now making
money. Baba I made I did 248 episodes
without super chats. You don't see that.
So Indians are like this nitpickers and
complainers and they don't like the
prospect of anybody making a little bit
of money from something. Right? That's
what India is like. That's what the
Indian population is like. It's very sad
to see this. So business doing business
is seen as a crime. Making money is seen
as a crime and business failure is also
seen as a crime in India. This whole
perspective, this whole mindset has to
be changed. And it starts with changing
the education system, it everything,
everything goes back. If you want to
change the quality of a society, if you
want to uh change the way so society
thinks, if you want to change a
society's perspective and viewpoint and
worldview, it has to start with the
education system. I've been saying that,
harping about this for years. So, let me
say it again. The education system needs
to be reformed. Let me say that with a
smile for a
change. Okay. Abishek Kare says
Manuspati how to counter if somebody
brings it. I have no idea what you're
asking. I like the Manuspriti.
Manuspriti is one of our great texts and
uh one of our great historical texts and
we have thousands tens of thousands of
historical texts and uh some people have
demonized the Manuspriti. I can show you
religious texts that are a million times
more toxic than anything you can than
any allegation you can make about the
manuspriti. So get the hell out of the
way those who are harping on that
manusmi is this or that.
Huh? So
yeah but anyway this is not my cup of
tea. This religious matter okay I don't
I don't address these
things. Okay. Okay. Vivi says uh I don't
know why India has painted as some
garbage land during independ during
independence. We were the second most
powerful nation in Asia at the time we
made the first Asian jet. It's all the
power of propaganda my dear friend. It's
all the power of propaganda. The truth
doesn't matter in the world. The age of
the west is the age of is the it's the
posttruth age. The west invented
something called propaganda. Of course
they didn't. They weren't the first to
invent it. we or we may have invented
it. I mean if you if you see uh Emperor
Ashoka's inscriptions everywhere, you
could say that that was
propaganda, you know, to some extent.
But anyway, the age of the West is the
post-truth age. Truth doesn't matter.
Only the only thing that matters is what
somebody repeats over and over and over
again. That's propaganda. So yeah, it's
this what you're saying is because of
propaganda. That's why certain um
certain narratives exist about
India. Animeh poll says, "How can we
build stronger national unity when many
are unaware of the geopolitical threats
we face? What role can citizens play
just beyond beyond the government and
armed forces in resisting propaganda and
safeguarding of our nation?" Look beyond
the governmentto government interactions
beyond the interactions between armed
forces and armed forces which is
warfare. Beyond that there is another uh
domain of warfare which is the warfare
on social media and it is social media
narratives that that essentially shape
the way the world thinks these days and
it shapes the way nations think. Now
social media platforms are owned by the
by the west which makes it very easy for
the west to to manipulate the the um the
world view of Indians and the way
Indians think and even the mood of the
nation. I promise you they have got big
dashboards on screens in the west which
show which show color-coded mood
charts mood maps of what the mood is
like in various parts of India about a
certain topic and then they can trend
trend certain things on Twitter and
other social media outlets and then
change the mood by doing
that. We saw a glimpse of that in prism
which was leaked by Edward Snowden more
than almost 15 years ago. If they could
do it at that time, imagine what they
can do today. And when it came to prism,
I think India was one of the top nations
under US
surveillance. Okay. Uh so I think that
if you want to build a stronger national
unity, uh you obviously aren't part of
the government. Majority of Indians
aren't part of the government or the
armed forces. But you can fight the good
fight on social media every day. Just
spend five minutes, you know, putting
out the truth about whatever matters to
you on social media. Everybody has
social media accounts, Instagram, um
Facebook, uh Twitter, YouTube, whatever
else I may have missed. So spend 5
minutes a day putting out something
positive about India put or countering
some some false narrative about India.
Just 5 minutes a day doesn't take much
of your time. So everybody if 1.4 4
billion Indians do that. Imagine the
effect of that. So that's how you can
build national unity uh etc.
Um, anonymous says, "Well, thank you
very much, sir. I'm doing well." Thank
you. But what's the followup? Okay, I'll
see. I'm sure there's there's a
follow-up somewhere. Thank you. Okay. K
says, "My theory, black hole equilibrium
via Higsfield integrity prevents
singularity. General general relativity
holds at core. Is it viable from an
extra physics view?" Uh, I can't say
just like that. If you can show me the
equations that you've worked out, then I
can look into it. Because see when it
comes to physics theories uh we have to
look at the equations without looking at
the equations you can't really tell
whether it holds because you know words
are vague and nebulous mathematical
equations are precise. So when I see
your equations that you must have
developed to you know as as the backbone
of the theory then I'll be able to
figure it out. So you know my email id
is down there in the des in the
description whatever calculations uh and
derivations you've done please email
that to me. I'll check it out and I'll
get back to you in case it is
worthwhile. Uh AJ Sharma says, "Why is
veganism or vegetarianism aggressively
promoted while or while Indian food is
called unhygienic, unhealthy on social
media, especially post Ukraine war any
hidden agenda? Post Ukraine war in
February 2022, Vladimir Putin launched
the special military operation uh to
denazify and whatever else Ukraine and
demilitarize Ukraine uh because Ukraine
was crossing uh NATO was crossing
Russia's red lines and India refused to
participate in the western sanctions and
other measures against Russia. Once
India refused to participate, we saw the
launch of a
coordinated slander
uh campaign against
India on social media and in the large
larger scale legacy media that is BBC,
CNN, Guardian, Lufigo and so on and so
forth so on so forth all the western
media outlets started this coordinated
campaign against India and uh western
media outlets BB eta they will do it at
a certain level. The think tanks think
tanks will do it at a different level.
And on social media, you can get down
and dirty and create all kinds of
disgusting memes about India. Right? So
all of this is a coordinated set of
actions. There's one single entity
behind all of
this. That's the that's the thing.
There's no hidden agenda. It's an open
agenda. It's about demonizing India. So
that in the future if India is punished
in some way, if something bad happens to
India, then nobody feels bad, right?
That's the deal. So for example,
operation zindur happens and for some
reason Pakistan wins, then the west will
say people in the west will not feel so
bad about this. That sort of
thing that tells you that tells you that
India needs to be very careful and very
serious about its defense. Uh nobody
will feel bad if something bad happens
to India and nobody will come to India's
rescue.
You rated Indian Navy view is at UK
Sanders Military
Academy. You rated Indian Could you
please explain in a little more detail?
I'm not able to decipher these things.
You rated Indian Navy
view. Okay. So the UK Sanders Military
Academy says India's Navy is not great.
Who the hell cares what the UK thinks?
The UK is a third rate military power.
The UK is a third rate world power. The
UK doesn't matter. The only importance
the UK has is first as the the US is lap
dog and secondly as the world's global
ep epicenter of moneyaundering. Beyond
that there's no other utility. The UK is
a poor nation attached to London which
is a milit which is a moneyaunder
moneyaundering hub the global
moneyaundering hub. That's
all. So I don't care what the UK Sanders
military academy thinks. I don't care.
Doesn't matter. They don't don't even
have their own nuclear deterrent. The
big red button sits in Washington. The
prime minister is anonymous. Nobody
knows who who the prime minister is. Is
it Rishi Sunak? Is it Theresa May? Is it
somebody else? Oh, these days it is
Starmer. Is it? Well, wait a couple of
weeks. Somebody else will come in.
Doesn't matter. The UK is irrelevant.
Anonymous says currently every computer
in the world is
is adeared to hierarchal organizational
structure
H every company in the world aderes to
hierarchal organizational structure ho
in which CEO is the highest authority
and CTO CFO etc. Yeah, there's a
hierarchy. Yes. Yes, there is. I agree.
uh in any organization if you want to
have an organization that functions
properly you need to have a hierarchy
you can't have a plain flat organization
it doesn't work I mean can you have the
sweeper do the or or the or the cleaner
or the janitor do the work of a computer
programmer can you have a computer
programmer do the job of a security
guard can you have a security guard do
the job of the of the of the chief uh
financial officer can you have the chief
financial officer do the job of the
chief executive officer and so and so
forth. It doesn't work, right? Everybody
has specialization. That's why so any
functional society, any functional
organization has a properly laid out
division of labor
structure. Turjjo says I'm a Bangladeshi
Hindu. 80% of Bangladeshi Bangladesh is
less is is about is less than 2 m above
sea level. 70% floods yearly. As the sea
levels rise, how should India respond to
this crisis? As the sea levels rise, we
should um we should uh offer asylum to
Bangladeshi
Hindus. I am totally in favor of that.
Give asylum in
India to all Bangladeshi Hindus. That's
what we should do. Beyond that, I have
nothing to say.
Anonymous says, "Does Barat have or had
any own organizational structure which
is better than the HOS? Did ancient Bat
had
companies?" Ancient Bat did not have
this great huge corporations as far as
we know. Ancient Bat had uh was you know
it's yeah it's a very interesting
question you're asking. Did did ancient
Bat have companies? You had guilds.
Guilds are are organiz not organizations
but communities.
uh close-knit communities of people who
are engaged in the same
profession. It's kind of tied to the
jati verna system that we used to have
and which has been destroyed. Uh jati
was typically occupation
based wasn't it? No. Jati was was
lineage based and vera was occupation
based and it was pretty complicated. It
was too complicated for the British to
wrap their heads around. So we did not
have any mega corporations as such but
we were a completely fully
industrialized
society and I think in bat in the
government you would have had an
organizational structure a proper
hierarchal organization structure as far
as we know well I I have never seen any
reference to any Indian corporation back
in the day before the Turk occupation uh
invasions
began. uh so yeah not sure about this
but that's a fascinating question you've
asked and I I wonder why Indian
historians have not tried to address
this
topic right so if yes how did they used
to operate and what was their
organizational structure as always
colossally proud as a distant student of
yours thank you and thank you to you as
well so like I said I am not sure I have
never come across any historical
document or book or whatever that speaks
about Indian corporations back in back
in the old days back in the days when
India was genuinely sovereign and
culturally and civilizationally
independent. Uh we know that we had all
the possible industries in the world,
metallological industries, ship building
industries, uh we uh textile industries,
arms manufacturing and whatnot.
Everything you could imagine, we had
that in the country. And this was all
decentralized. It was not like we have
five metropolitan cities and unless you
move to one of these big cities, you
won't have a job. No, people had jobs
wherever they were in the country. It
was the world's probably best economic
model. But as a as a consequence, you I
as far as I can see, it looks like we
did not have any mega
corporations. So I haven't seen evidence
of that and I haven't really even
thought about this thus far until you
asked me this question.
So yeah, now that you asked me the
question, I'm trying to recall from from
all my years of reading about Indian
history. I can't remember a single
reference in any history book about an
Indian corporation, a mega corporation
comparable to what you may have
today. Um, if you want to know about the
organization structure in the Indian
governance system during the Morin era,
uh, read the Artha Shastra. It's very
clearly laid out over there. But uh
corporate structure, no idea whatsoever.
So I am going to have to say I'm sorry.
I don't don't know. As far as I know,
nobody has written about this. If it did
exist, no historian has bothered to
research that which is surprising
because nobody has even mentioned that
we tried to research this and we could
not find anything which is
strange. Yeah.
Uh, Sumant Damarla says, "How can
somebody intercept ICBM with nuclear
warhead? If they intercept in space, a
nuclear explosion in space would be
catastrophic for Earth." Right? Not
right. Let me explain why. So, Starfish
Prime, let us Google Starfish Prime,
shall
we?
Starfish Prime. Let's look at the images
first.
This is what a nuclear explosion in
space looks
like. All right. Now, uh let's look at
the AI summary which is not necessarily
right but it will be the same quality as
Wikipedia. 1.4 megaton nuclear blast
conducted by the US in 62 detonated at a
high altitude 400 km over the Pacific
Ocean. Okay. So that's a big warhead 1.4
1.4 4 megat
ton. It created a significant EMP that's
disrupted power grids and communication
systems in Hawaii. It caused damage to
satellites in orbit uh and so on so
forth, etc. So, as you can see, a
nuclear explosion in space will not be
catastrophic for the earth. Now, that's
number one. Okay, that's number one.
Number two, if you take out an ICBM, you
if you smash it to bits and it has
nuclear warheads, those nuclear warheads
won't
explode. They are designed to explode
when when they reach the target. They
won't just randomly
explode. And even if they explode, let's
say, then you can see what happens.
Nothing happens. It's fine. It may
damage some satellites in
space.
Um perhaps but most likely I would say
not most likely but guaranteed they are
designed to not explode in
space because if if let's say let's say
the US launches an ICBM at Russia for
example. Okay. So the ICBM will exit the
atmosphere and then try to reenter the
atmosphere and let's say we have an exo
atmospheric interception. So we take out
the Russians take out the ICBM before it
can reenter the atmosphere. Maybe let's
say at 150 km or 200 km height
altitude and let's say the satellite the
ICBM has let's say 10 warheads and they
all explode. It I think the Americans
have way more satellites in space than
the than the Russians,
right? Will it cause will it not cause
more damage to the Americans? It will.
uh so the Americans will ensure that
whatever happens if the if the ICBM is
intercepted it will not result in the
detonation of the nuclear warheads. You
can build in safe failsafe measures to
ensure it doesn't
happen. It's the same thing like you
know what if India hits Pakistani
nuclear warhead storage sites will it
not cause nuclear explosions? Not
necessarily. It doesn't work like that.
Okay. So I hope that answers your
question. Ankita has gifted five Aijit
chart memberships. Thank you so much
ma'am. You're very kind. Thank you so
much. Uh confused fan says why is India
so passive? Why can't India play games
with China with respect to Taiwan or
Tibet? Because in the real world you can
play games to the extent to which you're
powerful. It's not a TV debate where
everybody can come and shout come and
shout at the same vocal volume. It's not
a TV debate. It's the real world. In the
real world, your ability to play games
is constrained by two things. One, your
power. Secondly, the power of your
adversary. If your adversary is four
times more powerful than you, then you
have very little space to play games.
Because when they start playing games,
it's going to affect you four times as
much. So, let's not get
all okay. The solution to this problem
is for India to become more powerful.
For that India has to work really really
hard for the next 15 20 years. No other
solution. So this is what happens. You
know this is what happens because of a
rotten education system. People can see
that India is not powerful and India is
being passive against China. But people
are not able to understand why it is
like this. Because the education system
my dear friends has not given you the
tools to understand how things work in
the world.
So you were like oh India is very
passive blah blah blah but you don't
understand why it is so what are the
things that are constraining India that
you don't understand because your
teachers your textbooks never taught you
anything you should be deeply deeply
disappointed with your teachers and with
your textbooks and your schools and
colleges and universities they did not
teach you anything you are completely
clueless today you don't understand why
India is not able to do so and so thing
or so and so thing against China and why
China can do this but India can't do it
because they did not teach you a thing
about these things. It's so
sad. Ramnat says,
"Rah, how did Russia bypass western
sanctions? What WTO India impact? How
did Russia bypass western sanctions?"
They didn't bypass any sanctions. They
just withtood the sanctions. Why?
Because they are an utarchy. They are
enormous land mass and they the land
mass is such that it is it it is it has
all the resources you need to have as a
civilization whether it's iron whether
it is copper whether it is coal whether
it is oil whether it is gas whether it
is agricultural products whether it is
uh chem chemicals whether it is
fertilizer whatever you want everything
is available in Russia you the Russians
have to import nothing so even if you
put all kind of sanction sanctions on
Russia it doesn't affect Russia Russia
that's the reason why Russia was able to
withstand the sanctions WT India Impact
I have no idea what you're asking so
sorry Charm Danesha says uh Israel
controls the US deep states apparently
this means they drive US policy and
actions it's very confusing US has sided
Pakistan but Israel India that's the
question I have raised multiple times
and nobody has an answer to this and
Charidesha is asking a very good
question say it's like this we know I
think nobody can deny by this that the
US has positioned Israel as its number
one ally. For some
reason, the US will never ever
ever do anything that will in any way,
big or small, hurt Israel's national
interest. The US will always offer
unconditional support to
Israel. Right? So it means that these
two are the closest allies you can
imagine anywhere in the world. The US
values Israel more than it values its
own mother country, the
UK. Right? So that's why many people say
that the Israelis control the US deep
state. Okay? Which means that they drive
US policies and actions. Fine, fair
enough. Lots of people say that now but
but Pakistan is a US vasal state and
Israel is India's friend. So what is
Israel's relationship with Pakistan?
That's the big question that people
don't answer in India because in India
people don't think right people don't
think in India in India we have full
support Israel full support
Israel people don't look even one layer
deeper what's the relationship between
Israel and Pakistan in the
1980s the Israelis had proposed a plan
to India that let's conduct a joint air
force operation
and we will destroy Pakistan's nuclear
reactor which was being built at the
cahuta or wherever. Okay. So the plan
was that Israeli air force fighter
planes will take off with Indian fighter
planes from air bases in western India
and we'll go and wipe out the Pakistani
nuclear reactor and and return to air
base. So that was the plan and it was it
almost went ahead but at the 11th hour
Israel pulled out of
it and that's why the Pakistani nuclear
program went ahead and maybe the
Pakistani nuclear program was just a was
just a cover for Pakistan requiring for
Pakistan acquiring US nuclear warheads
or whatever it is. So Israel walked out
of this thing at the last moment. Why
did Israel choose not to destroy
Pakistan's nuclear reactor and what's
the nature of the Israel Pakistan
relationship like today? These are these
are nebulous matters. There are big
question marks over these
things. The Israelis and Pakistanis
don't have official uh diplomatic
relations. Pakistan doesn't
recognize the the state of Israel and so
on. Pakistan says Israel is evil blah
blah blah. But what is the actual deal
is the question right and that there is
a lot of lot of
uh lot of vagueness big question mark
over
this because on the one hand Israel is
Israel is the US's biggest ally on the
other hand India and Israel have
excellent relations Pakistan is India's
second biggest enemy Pakistan is a US
vasal Israel and US best terms so what
is the Israel relationship relationship
with Pakistan and there are other
questions when it comes to Israel also
okay which I'll not go into over here so
it's an excellent question that Charby
has raised over here and it's a question
I think Israel should answer I
can't but it's a question that needs to
be asked so glad to have have this
question
today Jen says please come back to
normal or maintain question quality
we'll see about that sir
Anchul Singh says America series next
episode soon enough soon enough. I am I
am I I think I'm taking on too many
things at the same time. I am doing uh
these Q&As every week. Last week I did
five of
them. Okay, this is the fifth one for
this week. Right. Next week we will have
four. I'm also doing um I've also
restarted the Indian interest one
episode per week. Next week we will have
three episodes sorry two episodes of
geost strategy. I also have some
podcasts that I need to release and I
also have the understanding America
series that needs to continue. So I
think I'm juggling a lot of things right
now but it will come soon the next
episode. I already have some in the in
the can. So they'll come out
soon and I thank you for asking this
question. I'm glad that some people are
watching and understanding America and
the next episode will come out
reasonably soon.
Ritik Yiddui says, "Saw your tweet about
Japan. Why doesn't Japan bring in more
Indians who share similar values instead
of groups that may disrupt their
culture? Are they solving one problem
only to create another?" You see my dear
friends, in case you have been watching
this channel for some time, you will
know that Japan has lost control of its
destiny. Japan became a slave of another
country in 1945.
1945 was the year the American military
occupation of Japan started. In 1945 the
Americans wrote the Japanese
constitution. It was not written by
Japanese. It was written by the
Americans. And from 1945 until 2025, how
many years? 80 90 whatever it is. How
many years is it? Yeah. 80
years. In 80 years, not a word of that
constitution has changed. The Americans
have not allowed Japan to change a word
of the constitution. The Americans have
more than 130 permanent military bases
on Japanese soil. The Americans control
the Japanese economy. The Bank of Japan
can't do a thing without the approval of
the US generals who run the country. The
Japanese foreign policy is controlled by
the US. The Japanese economic policy is
controlled by the US. And now the
Americans have decided that we're going
to have invaders into Japan. The same
thing that's happening to Europe is now
going to happen to Japan. So you're
going to have Rohingya, you're going to
have Bangladeshies, you're going to have
God knows what else coming into
Japan. So it's not Japan's fault. It's
the Americans who are doing this. And
it's
sad. It's terribly sad.
Wamsh Kalam says if princely states are
puppets then Rajputs are too from Mgal
collaboration. So this is one allegation
that they keep raising about the
Rajputs. Uh the
Rajputs contributed more blood to the
country. They shed more blood to the
country than you can
imagine. They were the front line of
India's
defenses for close to 500
years. Ever since the Gandhara invasion
started, the Rajputs were doing the
fighting. the bleeding and the dying.
Eventually the Rajputs were broken
because of a lack of political unity.
Every Rajput kingdom fought bravely but
fought without uni unifying with the
others. So this went on for centuries.
Even 500 years after Gandhar fell, the
Rajputs were still fighting but
eventually they were broken and some
were
co-opted by by the Mughals. So that's
why this this slander has started that
Rajputs were mogul
collaborators. Well well it is just sad
to see this our our own Indian people
saying such things just sad you know and
this is a great example of how divided
India is. Indians like to you know
launch taunts and jibes at each other
and they feel good about this. Sad to
see this.
Eshwaria Sina says you've always
criticized Shri the the magnificent Shri
Naruji for his policies but you have to
agree on his fact that his non-aligned
position has made India a true sovereign
nation really you say so non the
non-aligned moment was a
stupidity India should have been
multi-aligned
madam multi-alignment is very where the
real juice is where the real um you know
that that's the that's the right policy
why be nonaligned
Non-aligned was a term that was an
excuse for being
mediocre. India should have played at at
the biggest and highest level of
geopolitics. India should have played
should have been friendly with all the
big powers without taking sides. And if
you do that properly, if you are a droid
in doing this, then you can really reap
the maximum benefits. But if you just
say that I'm non-aligned but you become
a puppet of the USSR. What kind of a
joke is that? Do you think India was
really
sovereign? Do you think India was really
sovereign in the during the 20th century
cold
war? You think so
ma'am? So India what should what India
should have done was India should have
been multi-line. We should have we
should have invited American investment.
We should have invited Russian
investment. We should have told America
that we are a better alternative to
China. You don't need to get into the
Chinese thing. We should have told
America, you don't need Pakistan. We are
there. We're going to do whatever you
want. Right? We would have told the
Russians, look, look, we are not
becoming American puppets. We're not
becoming their vasals or allies. We are
doing business with them. You are
welcome to invest in in India. So, play
that sort of game. It's difficult. It's
not impossible. It's happened many times
in the past. That's what India should
have done. That way India would have
been sovereign as well as India would
have become way richer than China and
way way earlier than than China and then
India could have played it played its
entirely own
game. So that is my position on this
ma'am. Uh Ritikui says did you watch the
Vijay Malia podcast your views? I don't
watch podcasts. I simply don't have the
time to watch podcasts and I haven't
watched the Vijay Malia podcast so I
don't have any views on that.
Prashant says, "If you get a chance to
interview the e external affairs
minister, what are my top questions?" I
don't know if if the opportunity arises,
I'm sure I will. You know, when I do a
podcast, it's not an interview. It's a
conversation. I usually speak about only
about uh 5% of the time I speak very
less. Generally, I want the other person
to talk. Um that's how I've always done
it. Um I'm not the person who will going
to you know inter intervene and
interfere and keep interrupting the per
the person I'm talking to but I never go
into a podcast session with a set of
questions in my
mind. I never have a sheet of paper only
once it happened because the other
gentleman insisted. I don't like it. I
never have a piece of paper with so with
with predetermined
questions. I always go into a podcast
with a completely empty mind and I start
the conversation and we'll see how it
goes. It only works if you have some
kind of understanding and knowledge of
of what the other person's domain and
field
is. So if I get to speak with our
external affairs minister in a podcast,
I will go in with an empty mind. But I'm
sure it'll be a fantastic podcast. So I
I don't know what I what I would talk
about right off if you ask me right now.
I have no idea. Maybe things will have
changed. Things will be different if
whenever this happens. If it happens.
Yeah. Charbby says why West does not
like India. We are only doing good. Live
peacefully and most prosperously
wherever we are. You see the west is not
like us. They don't like people living
peacefully. If you look at their
history, is it a history of allowing
people to live in peace?
It is a history of going where people
are minding their business and living
their lives and destroying those
cultures, genociding people, stealing
their land and then claiming to be the
upholders of human
rights. The west is the biggest problem
that the human civilization has
encountered in the past 500
years. So we India, we were enslaved by
the west for 250 years.
for a quarter
millennium.
They plundered everything of value out
of
India. They tampered with our society.
They tried to Christianize vast regions
of India. They imposed their
primitive barbaric systems on India,
institutions on India. Their inferior
governance system has been imposed on
India. They handed power to a set of
crooks etc. And the objective was that
by the time a few decades pass, India
will be completely destroyed. Its
culture will be uprooted. Civilization
will be
gone. But lo and behold, we are still
here. And uh when the British left, our
life expectancy was 31. The average
person was expected to live 31 years in
India. Our GDP per capita capital capita
was abysmal and so on. But we rose
again. We're growing again. And from the
western perspective, their their
attitude is how dare you still exist
after we ruled you and plundered you for
250 years. How dare you still survive
and how dare you still be
polytheistic and they are determined to
smash us into into oblivion. That's why
they don't like India. They hate
polytheists and they hate anybody who
doesn't have a white skin and they hate
anyone who can set a better example than
their system. So that's why they hate us
and they will not allow us to live
peacefully and mind our own business. So
there's going to be some kind of
reckoning
someday. Ritik Yagu Yaduanchi says Iscon
is blamed per live chat response. I have
no idea about that. I I have not
mentioned any anybody anywhere. So uh
Adit Kumar says is the news of Taiwan
asking for Indian readers true? Is it if
it is true why is America allowing this?
I haven't heard of this news. Okay,
let's let's Google it. Let's Google it
and see if it is true. If it has
appeared in the news. So, Thai uh sorry,
Taiwan
Indian radars.
Yeah, Taiwan is interested in uh that's
one second. I have to see the news news.
Where's the news? Resonant news. I don't
think that's a reliable source of
information business
today.
China D. Okay. So I am looking for a
properly established news outlet. China
gave Pakistan radar settle. We know
that.
Okay. So I think look I don't know what
this outlet is but I don't think it's a
major outlet. It's not I don't think
it's a outlet that can be regarded as a
as a reputable outlet. So I don't know.
in all these YouTube channels. I I don't
believe them. I mean, there's
no reason to to put too much credence
into what various YouTube channels say.
Despite me also being a YouTube channel,
I'm saying this, okay? Being very clear
about this. So, I don't know if this is
true. So, if it is not known to be true,
then we cannot speculate as to why the
US would allow it. So, I don't know.
Some people just for views and clicks
and whatnot will put out all kinds of
random news, madeup news. But uh yeah,
so you have to take these these all
these claims with a grain of
salt. Purina Singh says Pier Modi is
invited to the G7 just a week before the
summit. Something sinister has been
planned for. Credit GI Trump to or
credit Jump to try something foolish for
headlines. Um I don't think anything
sinister is being planned. I think the
Canadian new prime minister maybe he
wants to uh build some bridges with
India. Uh his predecessor Mr. Justin
Trudeau has had done more damage than
you can imagine to India Canada
relations. So maybe Mr. Carney wants to
repair the ties and it doesn't make I
mean the G7 loses relevance if if a
major power a major economy like India
is not invited. Um, so I don't think
anything sinister is being planned. Will
Trump try something foolish for
headlines? Well, only Trump will know
about that. Trump Trump is capable of
anything. Trump is a juvenile
irresponsible person. You never know
what he will do. But even he will not
cross certain lines. Hopefully, we'll
see about that. We'll see. Lavana says
CCP and USA weakening is good for
India. Brain
drain. CCP and USA weakening. Well, who
is saying that USA is weakening
anywhere? If USA weakens, well, it will
cause instability in the world.
Um, CCP weakening once again, I haven't
seen evidence of CCP weakening. So, I
don't know when if they're putting
restrictions on the American education
system and visas for Indians, then it'll
be good for India's brain drain. But
then the question is all these bright
minds who are not able to go to the US,
what will we do for them in India? Will
we give them the opportunities they
would have got in the US? That's the
question. Dr. Hershwadan Mo says, "Why
is Trump supporting Pakistan so openly
and saying Pakistan is strong leadership
and some people will not like what I'm
saying refers to
India?" Well, the US has invested in
Pakistan for decades. The US regards
India as a potential long-term enemy and
rival. Not enemy but rival. They see
that they see that they see that India
has the potential to be the next China
by a 2040 horizon. the next 15 years if
India keeps growing at 7 8% a year for
the next 15 years we're going to be the
next China and China by then will be a
very different country a weaker country
an older country an older population not
necessarily a weaker country but a very
different kind of country so then the US
will may have two rivals instead of just
one and they guess that you know if
India is right now acting so nice maybe
in the future it won't act so
nice so that's why they don't want India
to grow so for that Pakistan is
brilliant. Pakistan is a great asset to
have to keep India permanently off
balance, permanently worried. So
obviously Trump will support Pakistan
for that reason and they have
significant investments that have
recently come to light in Pakistan.
Apparently the Americans are operating
Nurhan air base. Apparently America is
operating a Nuran air base. So obviously
if they have such investments in
Pakistan and Trump's family has recently
invested in some Pakistani crypto
cryptocurrency scheme. So if they have
so many investments in Pakistan and they
see they see Pakistan as a valuable
nation then obviously they will support
Pakistan. Pratish thank you very much
sir. Thank
you even Lord thank you for extending
your
membership. Uh how did the Africaners
make desert farms
better? Well South Africa isn't really a
desert. South Africa has got good
terrain, excellent climate, very nice
cool climate, very similar to the
southern part of
Australia. Very nice climate. It's never
hot. It's pretty cold at times and so
on. And it's it's great for for
cultivation, for for agriculture, etc.
So the
Africaners exploited this wonderful
um terrain, the wonderful quality of
soil in a in southern Africa and they
did not build farms in
deserts. Uh they built farms in the
wealths of Africa, South Africa. Vel DT
felt uh that's the Africana word word
for field I would say or or prairie or
something. And they also had uh farming
operations in Nami in the Namibia
region. Now Namibia is more desertified.
Let's let's take a look at a the map. So
So that will give us some kind of uh
better
understanding. Let's look at the
map. So this is uh South
Africa. Now let's look at the terrain.
So I would imagine that the the Africana
farms would have been in the green
areas and uh as you can see there are
lots of lakes, lots of rivers and all.
So overall it's it's not really
desertified and if you look at the
satellite
image
satellite then I can assure you that
there are lots of opportunities for
using all this water for building farms.
So even where you would have terrain
that seems to be barren you have plenty
of water bodies. So I suppose that's
what they would have exploited all these
water bodies to to to build their farms
and in Namibia I'm sure the situation
would have been much much harder but
even there you have lots of water bodies
and so on. There is of course a Nib
Namibian desert over here which
obviously you don't want to farm in but
you want to get the diamonds from there
and yeah tremendous quantity of diamonds
you find in Namibia and so on. So I
think that's the deal.
So
yeah, now Ritik Edwini says, "Do you
think higher Indian authorities would
know what leverage Israel has over the
US other than the money control? Can we
develop that kind of
control?" I think the higher Indian
authorities would know what what
whatever leverage
exists. I think they would.
But I don't know what leverage exists.
And that's why I can't answer the second
part of your question. Can we develop
that kind of
control? So if I would possibly know
what the higher Indian authorities know,
then maybe I could give some some
insights as to how as to whether we can
first of all develop such kind of
control and if yes, then
how? Um I have some what what you would
call educated guesses as to what the
kind of leverage may exist but since
it's a guess and not a fact not a proven
fact so I can't say it in open so yeah
there you have
it okay vidyman says often talk about
what's often we often talk about what's
wrong with Indian education system and
end there along with nit nitpicking
cribbing without action is also our
classic trait. Well, if you see my
episodes 28 to 31 or whatever it is, I
have given detailed action plans on what
needs to happen. So, I am not a net
picker Viji
G. I have given detailed action plans on
in those three episodes very detailed as
to what needs to happen, what changes
need to be implemented.
as says queser mango are better than
alonso. Maybe maybe it's possible I I
love
mangoes. Uh Tipan says at the subatomic
level quarks of all elements are the
same. So is the entire universe made up
of one kind of matter? That is very
similar to ma
mahata maha
mahaatwa mentioned in the puranas.
What's your opinion? At the subatomic
level, the quarks of all elements are
the same. No, that's not the case. There
are six kinds of quarks. Up, down, top,
bottom, strange charm. See there in my
head, up, down, top, bottom, strange,
charm. These are the different kinds of
quarks that you have. And they are very
different. They've got very different uh
u masses and so on. Would you let's
let's quickly take a look at that. Yeah,
I'll put that on the screen. Let me
share some kind of graphic. I'm sure
there are graphics available.
Okay. Okay.
Quarks. Quarks. There we have it. So
yeah, up down but what are the masses?
Very different masses. Very different
properties and
characteristics. See this is in the
masses are going to be in terms of mega
electron volts per c. The up quark is
2.16 me by c^ squ. The down quark is 4.7
me. The charm quark is 1.27. The strange
quark is 93.5 mev. Wait till you see
more. The top quark is 172.5 GV per c^
squ. Okay. Even the charm cork is in GV
and uh the bottom quark is 4.183 GV. So
the top quark is super massive
1.72.57 G V per squared. The up quark is
tiny in comparison uh to that.
So the quirks are very different very
very very very different from each
other. It is not one single ta there are
a whole bunch of different
twas
right Amisha Mishra says why Akbar is
called the great in history. Let us
begin this practice of calling this
individual by his real name. I mean why
call him why give him a fake name? What
was his name? His name was Jalal Udin.
Jalal Udin. Let's let's Google. Uh here
we have
it.
Okay. Jalal Udin, Turic King. Jalal
Odin. Look at this. Look at this. Look
at this. Okay. I'm not talking about
Mangabi. I'm talking about Jalal Oudin.
Mughal. Okay.
Mughal Mughal king see Akbar Jalaludin
Muhammad Akbar. So if you if you search
for Jalaluduin Turk king they will give
you Jalaluduin Mangaborni or Jalaluduin
the
coward who ran from Chingish Khan and
found refuge in India right but this
fellow who is called Jalal who called
Akbar his real name was Jalal Udin. So
let's call him Jalaludin. Why give him a
fake name? Akbar which means great.
Akbar the greatness. Great. The great
Akbar is a is a Arabic word. So let's
call the the the individual jaludin.
That would be a better way. That's a
better practice, isn't it? It's more
accurate. Anonymous says how can we
bring political unity? How were we
united during Morin and Kadeshka Empire?
What steps did these magnificent rulers
take to do so?
Strength.
Strength. You need a leader of
exceptional strength. A leader who is
who has the qualities that can unify an
entire subcontinent. Very few people can
do such things. The last such person who
gave rise to an empire like this was
Chhatrapati Shivaji Baharaj. And he
himself was the ruler of a reasonably
modest dominion compared to what the
Marata empire eventually became.
Compared to that the dominion that
Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj ruled over
was modest in size. But he was the
founder. It was his vision that gave
rise to the Marata Empire. So what did
Kaneshka the great do? What was his what
steps did he take? He conquered. He
destroyed all his enemies. He defeated
everybody.
What did uh Chandra Gupta Mari do? He
defeated the Nanda Empire. He grabbed
power and he consolidated power. So what
is the one characteristic that all these
great rulers share?
Strength. Strength. And not saying no. I
mean not not allowing anyone to say no
to you. Oh, this can't be done. No, I'll
do it. That's what you need. You need a
superman essentially to unite the
subcontinent. That's what you need. Not
some random two-bit leader who can give
great speeches. I'm not I'm not
mentioning anybody by name by the
way. So don't try to put words in my
mouth. I we have had so many so-called
leaders in India in the past 80 years.
Huh? Who are all words words who are all
talk talk great at giving speeches but
no action. Thankfully things are
changing now but we need real supermen.
If you want to bring back the days of
the Morian and Kushan empires and Gupta
empire even Chola Empire or Marata
Empire you need a
superman.
Okay light Yagami. Thank you very much
sir for your contribution. Appreciate
it. Shiva Rajput says Illuminati any
evidence of them existing? Well, if a
story refuses to go away, maybe there's
some truth to it, but uh what's the
evidence? Flimsy thus far, but you know,
who
knows? But a story that refuses to go
away. That's
interesting. Even Lord says, "Do you
suspect that the step peoples, the
Turks, the protogerermanics and Slavs
are more aggressive than the from the
brutal environment? How do you think the
Western peoples will be if they become
Islamic?" Look, your environment shapes
who you are.
Why did all the monotheistic religions
emerge from desert
environments? Why uh and these
monotheistic religions or all had very
brutal practices? Right? You could say
have so why did they all emerge from
desert environments? Why did
polytheistic religions emerge from you
know lush lush green
environments where there is a lack of
the horrible desert uh kind of
terrain
right even um so that's that's one
example of how your environment shapes
who you are your it shapes your culture
it shapes your religious outlook it
shapes your lifestyle now if you're
living in the step vast open grasslands
with very little resources except for
grass. Very difficult to survive there.
You need to be a real hunter and small
group of groups of people need to be
very agile, very nomadic. They to band
together and they have to compete with
other groups of people people for the
little resources that exist. So if you
if you have such an environment, you're
going to have a very aggressive mindset.
So that's why the Turks were like that.
Even the Mongols had that sort of
existence until they were unified under
one empire. Um, so yes, your environment
matters of even the temperature matters.
If you live in a very cold environment,
you're going to be much hardier than
people who live in a very hot
environment. If you live in a hot
environment, you're going to be
lethargic. You're going to be sluggish.
You will be less productive. If you live
in a cold environment, you're going to
be way more productive. You're going to
be way more active.
It's just the way it is. So I think one
of the disadvantages India has is the
hot
weather. Maybe we need to expand to a
place where there is colder weather. I
wonder where that could be. Just saying.
Okay. Not recommending
anything. Light says if the Philippines
is a US vasal, so why are we selling
them bramos? Maybe we want to wean them
away. Maybe we want to wean them away
from the US. Perhaps maybe there'll be
some restrictions or something.
Manik says, "Why can't we give nukes to
Taiwan to counter China?" Because Taiwan
is America's vasal. If we give them
nukes, the Americans will figure out
everything we've done, all our
technological secrets. We can't do
it. Millerin says, "Why do people
justify reservations saying it justifies
the crimes done to them? They are even
exempted from college fees irrespective
of their annual income." This is all
part of the old nonsense that that we
have been laboring under. It all starts
from the Arian invasion myth that some
white people came and invaded India
which was which was inhabited by black
people and we uh the white people they
enslaved the the natives who were
apparently Dravidians enslaved them and
subjugated them and brutalized them and
forced them to move to India south and
then imposed this evil foreign Hinduism
and the evil foreign cast system on all
on everybody who lived in India and the
people who live in the north are
descendants of the whites. So we are
Arian invaders and we have been
oppressing the natives for for thousands
of years and we created the cast system
which means everybody who is supposedly
low cast has also been oppressed by us
for thousands of years. So now we have
to
pay this all of this nonsense comes from
the RN invasion theory and that's why I
have been fighting against the RN
invasion theory since 2017 whenever it
was when I wrote the first
article. It's the root cause of all this
nonsense is the RN invasion theory which
is why we need a reform a set of reforms
on the Indian education system otherwise
this nonsense will go on forever and
India will never rise beyond this petty
nonsense excuse me one
second
okay Bora says is forgetting part of
history parts of history, a form of
healing or a dangerous
ignorance. If great empires always fall,
what lessons are we failing to learn
from
them? Forgetting history is not a form
of healing, it's a form of stupidity or
or like you say, dangerous ignorance.
Because if you forget parts, you know,
parts of history that are painful. Let's
say the past 1,000 years of Indian
humiliation when we were uh occupied by
foreign powers. first the barbaric Turks
and then the barbaric Europeans, right?
If we forget all that happened and why
it happened and how how we were
oppressed and so on, then it's very easy
for us to to fall prey to that all over
again. So, it is very dangerous to
forget history. We should remember
everything. We should document
everything so that we know where we went
wrong, what things went wrong, what
mistakes we did and how we can ensure
this never happens again. And also what
were the t tactics and strategies of of
the barbarians. So we document
everything. We we understand more about
them. Now if great empires always fall,
what lessons are you failing to learn
from them? Well, there's there's a
pattern to the rise and fall of every
empire. It's a cyclical process. In in
China, you call it the dynastic cycles
and so on. So if you study that, you
will know that there are certain factors
that contribute to an empire's fall. And
if you avoid those factors, then you
will you'll be fine.
Shubam Dubet says, "I believe our
country is on the right
path. How can the youth contribute more
to the
motherland and help
India, excuse me, and help make India
great
again?" The youth, what can they do to
contribute more to the motherland? First
of all, stop all this petty infighting.
This
what whatever infighting exists stop
stop all that regional infighting region
versus region linguistic in fighting
language against language all this is a
waste of your
time. What the youth should do is find
whatever aptitude, whatever your best,
whatever you're good at, whatever your
true aptitudes are, set of set of
characteristics, set of aptitudes,
acquire the skills that are relevant to
all of that and contribute what you can
to society to the best of your
ability and cooperate and collaborate in
doing this. That's how you make India
great again. One person individually can
do a thing but if we all work together
and collaborate and cooperate we can
achieve miracles that's what we can
do. Sumit Garbal says green res
revolution destroyed high protein wheats
for high yield. Uh the green revolution
was a disaster actually for India. Yeah
for a short time you can say that yeah
every Indian got more wheat to eat and
all that but it destroyed the
biodiversity we had. We had so many
different kinds of grains in India.
Today it's everybody just eats like two
grains. One kind of wheat perhaps like
three four different kinds of rice.
That's about it. We had I mean for
thousands of years people in India used
to eat other grains as much as wheat and
rice. Grains like bajra and jawir. They
have completely been marginalized today.
There are very few people who eat that.
I know it's still
available but where's the demand for it?
I I'm sure they are actually probably
healthier than the wheat that was that
is now prevalent as a consequence of the
green
revolution. So the green revolution was
a short-term success but long-term it's
not been good for India. It's it's kind
of been uh bad for our our biodiversity
and for our traditional diets.
Um, can the French kill switch Rafal if
the US pressurizes a lot? Only if they
can come to India and open up the Rafal
and put some kill switches
inside. God of Singh says,
um, what are the major evidences that we
have that prove that the age of the
submerged duara to be under 12,000 years
old and are there any other sunken
cities from the past present in the
coastlines of India? uh they recently de
discovered a new new as in old sunken
city of the coast of Tamil Nadu not very
far away from present day Pondicherryi
under the ocean obviously it's possibly
the ancient city of
cavatnam which uh if you look at its
depth under the ocean it's at a depth of
maybe 150 m or something if it is at a
depth of approx okay let's just quickly
Google it
okay quickly google it so that I giving
you the right information. A submerged
uh
submerged
submerged cavary
[Music]
cavi
pin. Okay, let's see what
puminum there has to be. Okay. Pum puhar
they call it because the new
pronunciations have to be the way they
are. Okay. So what have they
found? What is this
nonsense? I'm not going to pay you for
this nons. Okay. So we get the
information right here. Depth of about
50 to 100 m about 30 to 40 km of the
coast of the present day Puhar in
whatever this is this district is. So
let's say it's at a depth of about a 100
m 50 to 100 m. let's say 100 mters. So
when was the last time that part of the
ocean was above ground and it would have
been sign it can be at sea level. It has
to be slightly above sea level maybe 5 m
above sea level or whatever. So whatever
time period that is that must be about I
don't know 10,000 years that itself
tells you how old the city is. When it
comes to Dara there are two pieces of
evidence. First of all, the depth at
which barca
exists that part of the subsurf sub
ocean surface sub ocean uh region uh if
we go back to the ice age and all in the
in the the sea levels of the time. I
think it goes back about 10,000 years.
So the last time that region was above
the ocean was about 10,000 years ago.
And secondly, they have uh they were
able to to dredge out a piece of ancient
wood from that sunken city and it was
carbon dated to about 8,000 something
years old before today. So these are two
pieces of evidence which give us some
kind of evidence about how old the city
possibly would be. I think the the two
pieces of evidence are not entirely in
synchronization with each other, but
they are
both showing that it's a very ancient
city for sure.
Ryik, thank you very much and welcome to
membership. Thank
you Geopolitical Dubet. Thank you so
much sir. Thank you. Uh Tarakarama
says what do you think about the
satwahanas and the and the role in
modern bharat? Should we follow the much
better saka samwat calendar that follows
the lunar cycle and ends with Gregorian
which has no logic? Uh the Satwahanas
are an ancient dynasty. I'm not sure
what their role in modern bat is. Um so
I'm not sure how to answer that question
but obviously one of the great uh great
great uh kingdoms and and dynasties in
in in Bat for sure. When it comes to the
calendar question, I think it makes
sense to follow the indigenous Indian
calendar which is way more much more in
synchron synchronicity with India's
weather cycles and it is way more
accurate than the Gregorian calendar for
sure. U and uh when it comes to the
calendars, we have different calendars.
We have the Saka Samwat current calendar
which uh dates which goes back about
2,000 years. And if you want to really
go back to the original calendar which
that would be the satish calendar
which so when came to India and he was
the Greek ambassador in partra which is
about 2 and a half thousand years ago he
said that the Indians have the saturi
calendar which goes back 6,000 plus
years. So 2 and a half thousand years
ago he was talking about a calendar that
went back more than 6,000 years. So the
actual original Indian calendar, the the
oldest one we know of, it started more
than 8 and a half thousand years before
today. So yeah, maybe we
can go back to
that. Stark Vincent said says, "Where
did India's looted wealth go funded the
US?" No, India's well funded the British
Empire and their military expansion and
and their colonial and the colonial
enterprises and their empire building um
enterprises. Uh so it funded all their
colonial activities, all their imperial
activities. India was the crown jewel of
the British Empire and whatever wealth
was amassed by various families where it
became part of the it was redistributed
all over the place in Europe because
these families did not belong to one
nation they belong the the for example
the royal families the royal families in
Europe whether it's the Dutch royal
family or the Russian earthwild royal
family the British royal family or or or
the Spanish royal family or whatever
else they are all part of the same
extended family they all blood
relationships. So all the wealth would
be eventually redistributed all over the
place and it's impossible to find where
it is today. And I'm sure it's made some
families incredibly wealthy and maybe
these are the families that are part of
the deep state and control the
world. Possibly.
Possibly. Vivya Sharma says, "Can China
flood our far east by opening dams?"
Watch episode 3 of Geost Strategy with
Abijit Chabda on this
channel in which I have answered this
question in extreme detail. The short
answer is
no. Ritik Yiddanchi says did the sun
actually set on the British Empire? As
you have mentioned, their headquarters
moved from Britain to Washington. It
means the empire survived. The empire
thrives. No. When they said that the sun
never set on the British Empire, it
means means that the British Empire had
possessions all across the world. So it
you never had a time when there was one
part of the British
Empire which see it means that wherever
you were in the world, wherever the sun
was shining, some part of it was shining
on a on a British Empire asset. That's
what it means. Uh but like you say I
like referring to me which I have said
that the headquarters has merely moved
from London to Washington DC. It means
the empire has absolutely survived and
it's thriving. It has simply been
rebranded. The empire the exact same
empire exists. It's simply been been
rebranded. Uh or or rather it's been
hidden. It's been hidden
away. Okay. Okay. So the US is is the is
the leader of the free world. So that is
the title they've given themselves which
means that they are the inheritors of
the British Empire. The leader of the
free world superpower. They have more
than 700 extr territorial military bases
with with and all they control all the
supply chains and trade routes and
everything and that's how they rule the
world. That's the hallmark of an empire.
That's what an empire does wherever it
in whichever geographical region it
controls. And the US does it all over
the world. So it's a superpower. It's
the inheritor of the British Empire. And
the British Empire still continues, but
now it's called whatever it's called
today. It's the US empire.
Now I think I already answered this qu
this question. I'm not sure why it's
coming again. But anyway, thank you
sir. Jati Vari says any geopolitical and
trade benefits of having synth? It's
part
of Sind well first of all geopolitical
benefit one major port returns to India
Karachi Karachi was called Mina nagar
200 years ago when it was ruled by the
great Chhatraa Mahakhatraba
Nahapana have you heard of Nahabana
great king no one remembers him he was
the ruler of the of the Indian west of
the western part of India and one of the
great ports he ruled over was Minandagar
which was Karachi. So if we get say in
the back we get Karachi which is a great
port wonderful port we would love to
have it. So we can trade from there and
we can also have naval base over there.
So yeah that's one example and I'm sure
there's many more. Uh and of course
beyond geopolitical and trade it's part
of our ancient
civilizational heritage. this region
it's always been part of batw we should
have it
back hab oh thank you so much sir thank
you kuml bora says um did leaders within
India's own freedom struggle sabotage or
suppressandra bos because they
challenged Gandhi and Nehu's
dominance I may have to give you some
evidence shall we Uh okay.
Neu
Neu letter
about Bose. Now
this yeah the BBC will call it a fake
letter. Obviously they will call it a
fake letter and alt news will say it is
fake and the Hindu will say it's fake.
Right. So where's the letter? Can you
please show us the letter? They want
Okay. Okay. So over here they've they've
uh you
know they've given a letter they've
shown a letter with with spelling
mistakes to make it look like it's fake.
But let's see if there's the original
image
somewhere
here.
Um okay let's see. So over here it's
clearly that uh it's clear that there
there's a spelling mistake over here
which Mr. Neu would never do.
Mr. Nu would never have a do a spelling
mistake. He was he was very fond of the
British
etc. Uh but what does it say over here?
Dear Mr. Atley, I understand from a
reliable source that Subas Chandra Bose,
your war criminal has been allowed to
enter Russian territory by Stalin. This
is clear treachery and a betrayal of
your faith by the Russians. As Russia
has been an ally of the British
Americans, it should not have been done.
Please take note of it and do what you
consider proper and fit. You are
sincerely Javal Neu. I don't see any
date etc over here. Uh and in this
letter it says
that Mr. Bose is a war criminal or your
war
criminal. Um and so on and so forth. I'm
not sure how true or reliable this is.
Lots of uh fact fact checkers are
calling this a forgery. The BBC is
calling this a fake
letter. So but it's
clear even if this letter let's say it's
it's fake. H um it's clear that there
was a tremendous amount of
animosity towards Mr. Bose when it came
to the leaders of the Indian National
Congress. Whether it was Mr. Gandhi, Mr.
Neu or whoever else they didn't like
him. They wanted him out of the way
because he wanted a very different kind
of India from what they wanted. They
wanted an India which was even after
so-called independence, it would remain
the same way the British had left it.
And Mr. Bose wanted a completely
different
India. So yeah,
um Vidy Manar says since you once said
the British had destroyed our food
ecosystem and and changed our food
habits, then
what was our original food system
habits? what was it like? So, it's very
difficult to tell you in in a few
minutes, but it's a good question that
you're raising. So, let me try and give
you some direction as to how you can do
your own research about this. So, let's
see. Okay.
Manus, it's an ancient book. It was
written in the 1100s by the Kalyani
Chalukia king Sumeshwara III. Okay. Now,
if you want to read this thing, maybe we
can try this one. We won't have it, but
the Americans will have
it. And let's wait for it to
open. And here we have it. So, it's
going to go into all kinds of things
into including food. Uh, okay. This
seems to be the Sanskrit version of it.
Do they have an English translation
somewhere?
Um I'm sure there's okay maybe on the
internet archive you may get
it.
Um but anyway my point is that if you
read this book and it's available may
pretty much for free
online then you will be able to get an
get an get insights into what our food
habits were like back in the day. Uh so
this book um what's it about? It talks
about once again this is Wikipedia which
is not necessarily a reliable source of
information. It all it always distorts
in your history but let's quickly take a
look over here for the sake of saving
time. Uh it talks about the how to gain
a kingdom, how to do governance,
economics, infrastructure, architecture,
medicine, cuisine, ornaments, perfumery,
love game, sports, jewelry, painting,
music and dance. And it has recipes etc.
It describes foods that continue to be
part of Indian modern Indian tradition.
Dosaka, Idarika, vataka,
parika, shirata, dhiada and so on. meat
dishes. Obviously, you will not have
meat of cow, horse, elephant, parrot,
peacock or eggs, but you have other
kinds of meat dishes and so on. So, if
you read this book, then you will have a
good understanding of what our culinary
practices were like maybe a thousand
years ago. Now, this is something that
be more maybe more applicable to the
cuisine of southern India, but it does
give you a good idea of how old ancient
Indian cuisine was like.
So Shreas says Rafals performed well in
operation sindur but France didn't
openly support India. Why the silence
despite the jet success? Why does France
need to support
India? This is a matter that doesn't
concern
France. India and Pakistan fight. How
does it concern France? Tomorrow France
and Belgium fight. Should we start
supporting one party or another? We stay
out of it. My
friends, why does France have to support
India or or say
anything? The fact that they have sold
Rafals to India is enough to count as
support. Why do Indians Why are Indians
obsessed with
words? Oh, but they didn't say
anything. They sold Rafals to India.
That is the kind of support that counts
as support for me. I don't care about
words or absence of words. Please learn
to look at the world in a different way.
Only actions matter. Words are
meaningless,
pointless. Gorav Singh says, "Is there
any geological evidence of people living
in India during the ice age? Was it an
advanced civilization as claimed by
Dlesh
Oak?" Look, evidence of people living
in a geographical region is not
geological evidence. It's called
archaeological evidence.
Okay. Um, we have found evidence. Okay.
Let's let's uh look, we know about
Indians, people living in India before
the ice
age. Now, have we found
u have we found skeletons of ancient
Indians from during the ice age time?
I'm not sure about I've not looked into
it. But I remember I had looked at uh I
had read a research paper about people
living in the gangetic in the Ganga
Valley region about 30,000 years ago.
They had found skeletons all 6 ft tall,
men, women, etc. and so on. So we had so
we have evidence of ancient Indians from
about 30,000 years ago. Um we also have
evidence of
agriculture now. Oh yeah, agriculture
and I have I have short videos on this
channel in which I speak about the
agricultural evidence. We have evidence
of agriculture in India that dates back
17,000 years which is smack bang in the
period of the ice age. So agriculture
only happens when humans do it, right?
So yes, we have archaeological evidence
of humans, people living in India during
the ice age. And why would anybody be
surprised? India was the original
founder zone of the outer of Africa
migration. So we we are the originators
of agriculture. Agriculture did not
emerge in the so-called fertile crescent
10,000 years ago. It may have emerged
there independently or not but it first
emerged in India in the Indian
subcontinent at least 17,000 years
before that which obviously tells you
that we were an advanced civilization.
So I I think that should answer your
question sir.
This has nothing to do with either
geopolitics or history or science. So I
will not take it. I I think I've been
very clear and I've put out the pinned
comment. Right? So so why do this sir?
Why I've said I will only take questions
about history, geopolitic science. So
please let's stick to that. Riku Yaduani
says will we ever arm Hindus in border
countries facing persecution? How long
must they flee? If government won't act,
should private forces time to revive
warrior spirit and grow in strength even
demographically?
Listen, if we Okay, now how do I deal
with this? This is again a religious
question, right?
I think India should uh provide all
assistance that is needed to Hindus who
are facing persecution whether it is in
East Pakistan or West Pakistan or
wherever else or whether it is Hindus
who are being persecuted by Rohhingyas
in
Myanmar India should provide all
possible all necessary assistance to
them including arming them and I don't
think there is anything wrong with that
so I think the government should do that
if the government for whatever reason is
not able to do Maybe private forces can
do it. So yeah, I would agree with
you. Jay Thiari says, "Can India rise
without compromising dharma?"
Absolutely. Absolutely. There is no
dharma without ara by the way. So ara is
necessary. There there cannot be dharma
without ara. There can't be dharma
without
money. So India needs to rise and once
we rise, dharma will be strengthened.
So I think yes India can rise without
compromising
dharma. Thoughts on Ashton Hall? The guy
on Instagram. I follow him on Instagram.
He's very entertaining. Always a new
video every day. Yeah, he's fun. He's
fun to
watch.
Okay is giving a recommendation of a
podcast. Well, thank you for your
recommendation. Thank you
sir. Okay. So now let's take some more
questions.
Um,
says, "How does an air defense system
identify between a friendly aircraft and
a hostile?"
Hostile hostile
aircraft. Uh, you have a a something
something called an iff system. IFF
system. What does it mean? If, friend,
or foe. So, it's an electronic system
which tells you that this thing that I'm
seeing on the screen isn't my thing or
the other guy's thing. So that's how it
is done. And Mclovin says PM Modi to
mediate between Elon Musk and Trump.
That'll be fun, won't it? That will be
fun. Mr. Modi mediating between Mr. Musk
and Mr. Trump. Okay, let's take some
more questions.
Um, did Mussolini says Tmay Pant also
believe in racial theory? Well,
Mussolini did believe that the Italians
were some kind of a superior race for
sure. So, he he kind of believed in what
this this Arian this this fake Arian
thing was of the Nazis. The Nazis
believed that they were of the Arian
race, the superior mench race and all
white people were Arians and the
Italians are also part of them because
they were they were the they were the uh
the continuation or the or the uh in the
legacy of the Roman
Empire. Uh obviously this Arian thing
was completely it was it was a lie
obviously.
Um and it's it's it's something that the
west stole from India but it is what it
is. So yeah, Mussolini also kind of
believed in all of
that. Okay. Raj says 1947 independence
or just transfer of power. I think I've
said this a million times. I've been
saying this for four years.
1947 was a transfer of power from one
set of crooks to a different set of
crooks. All right. There we have it.
Okay, Vishal says, "What's the Ryman
hypothesis and why is it so
significant?" Well, the Ryman Ry Ryman
hypothesis is a conjecture in number
theory. It's about the distribution of
prime numbers and it says that uh all
non-trivial zeros of the Ryman Za
function have a real part of 1 by two.
That's the Ryman hypothesis and it's
it's
it's something that uh KL Ryman put
forth a long I think his name was KL
Ryman was
it? He he put that up a long time ago.
When was that? I'm I'm sure it was it's
more than a century ago and his name was
not KL Ryman. His name was Bernard
Ryman. And this has stood the test of
time for I think uh 150 or so years. And
it's uh Grigori Perilman who was able to
finally uh solve it. So it's it's
significant because it's one of the long
it was significant because it was one of
the longest uh standing hypothesis that
stood the test of time. Nobody was a
able to either prove or disprove it
until the the Russian genius Gregori
Perilman was able to finally prove it.
And the Chinese mathematician, what was
his name?
Yao, I forget his name. I the Chinese
names are so hard to remember but one of
a very famous Chinese mathematician
tried to steal Perelman's achievement
because Perilman did not publish this in
a peer-reviewed paper in a peer-reviewed
journal he published he put his paper up
on the physics archive where anybody can
put a physics paper essentially or
mathematics paper or scientific paper so
he just put it up on the physics on the
archive and there that was it. So the
Chinese guy uh let me let me quickly uh
show you the evidence of that.
Um yeah.
Um
manifold what's it called? Manifold
legacy or manu manifold destiny.
Manifold destiny. So what was this guy's
name? Yeah. Shingong Yao this fellow
tried to steal Perilman's
achievement. Anyhow, so that's what
happened. Yeah. So that's about
the
conjecture. Um what else do we have?
What else do we have?
Um Kamill Bora says, "How could a
religious system claiming cosmic truth
justify untouchability and hereditary
inequality?" I'm not sure which
Abrahamic system you're talking about,
but no Abrahamic system claims cosmic. I
think they all claim cosmic truth. I'm
not sure. Do the Abrahamics have
untouchability? Because we don't have
it. Hereditary inequality. The
Abrahamics do have it. Yeah. Uh so yeah,
I mean that's what happens. You know
what can I say? Jay Tari, well thank you
so much for becoming member.
Um Shikhan says, "Do you don't want
Karachi with that population? Secondly,
Kavari any good investing or
import? I have no idea what all this is.
I agree that yeah, Karachi has that
population. I know a radicalized
population. Obviously, it doesn't make
sense to have that
population. I'm I'm talking about the
port. The port is great, but the
population is deeply deeply uh
problematic. So, I completely agree with
you on that. So we would like the port
but the population u is very problematic
and yeah so that that's an issue.
Second, Cavari. Any good investing or
import engine technology? Cavari engine.
You're talking
about caviar
engine. Okay. Cavary engine. We're going
to keep keep working on it. I suppose.
And if we get some kind of technology
transfer proposal, maybe from Russia,
maybe for France, we can consider it. If
it is a proper proposal with full
technology transfer, we should go for
it. no matter
how how
how expensive it is. Okay. And
uh does the US have super intelligent or
sentient AI? I have no idea. I suppose
they have very powerful AIs that nobody
knows about but I don't know about
whether they are sentient or not. Harjab
says my thoughts on the ER er is equal
to EPR paper in physics. the ER is equal
to EPR paper the the concept it's uh
it's a proposition in theoretical
physics which suggests a fundamental
connection between two very different
concepts the Einstein hosen bridges
which is er and the Einstein podolski
roen paradox which is the ep what's an
Einstein roen bridge I have spoken about
this so many times it's called
colloially a wormhole. A
wormhole. So, er is is wormholes that
that connect black holes. EPR is the
quantum entanglement of particles. So,
where you measure one particle's
properties and you'll instantly know the
properties of the other particle, right?
That sort of thing. So the ER is equal
to EPR
uh concept say it postulates that these
two seemingly unrelated phenomena are
essentially the same thing essentially
two sides of the same coin. So that's
what the ER er is equal to EPR thing is
and it's a pretty I think it's a pretty
solid concept.
Okay, let's Okay, now I I'll do this for
another five minutes and then I'm done.
So, in case you're planning to purchase
super chats, please stop because yeah,
we are at the end almost at the end of
today's episode. Pranum Kumar says India
needs artistic infrastructure new
temples now. I would love to have that.
Yes, I
agree. Rohan is talking about religion.
I have said that I will not talk about I
will talk about geopolitics, history and
science today. So, I cannot take this
question. Please, if I have said it very
clearly, why do you have this? You're
wasting your money, sir. I am not going
to discuss these
things. Joy Tari says, "If you were
India's PM for 10 years, what grand
strategy would you implement to
decisively counter China and make India
the leading Asian power?" If I were
India's PM for 10 years, I would ensure
that I become India's PM for a 100
years. That's number one. Number two, I
mean that's that's a joke obviously,
right?
I would um you know do whatever it takes
to have as rapid economic growth as
possible as rapid and as massive as pos
possible whatever roadblocks exist I
would make it my life's mission to
eradicate those
roadblocks and long-term things I would
do I would reform India India's
education system I would I would launch
a war on corruption I would be very
unpopular as a consequence but I would
do all these things only then Will we
become India's leading power? Otherwise,
it won't
happen. Okay. Bharab says although India
stopped quite early, India did announce
new normal. You're talking about
operation synindor. Even the MP
delegations are not trying to convince
the world. So is India finally getting
ready to stand up for itself against the
west. I think India is rising. India is
becoming more
capable. India is becoming as a
consequence more self-confident.
uh the MP delegations well it's not a
bad idea especially to the global south
nations when it comes to sending an MP
delegation to the to the US I think it's
a waste of time the US is not going to
be convinced they don't care about what
India says okay but sending MP
delegations to the global south
countries is a very good idea so that
was great and we have indeed announced a
new normal we have indeed announced a
completely new doctrine when it comes to
Pakistan the Pakistanis know it now If
there is a terrorist attack someday in
the future anywhere in India, it means
war with
Pakistan, right? So yes, India is is
it's a different India. India is
changing. India is evolving. I'm not
sure if India is standing up uh standing
by itself against the West, but India is
showing to the west that you know, you
have been using this this terrorist
puppet of yours against us for so long,
but now sooner or later we're going to
smash it. We're going to end it
completely. And we are not worried about
your nuclear blackmail. See, you
understand now it's becoming very clear
now that the Pakistani nuclear blackmail
is actually western nuclear blackmail
against us. So
um Aryan Thiagi says Sudguru G once said
in India today conclave. Okay. India
should have elections once in 8 years
until we reach at least 12 trillion
dollar economy. What are my views on
that? Okay, not a bad idea. We can try
it. There's no harm in trying something
different. what we have been doing for
the past 70 80 years it's not worked out
great. There's no harm in trying a
different approach. Or maybe well,
what's the what's the advantage of
having an 8-ear cycle instead of 5 year
cycle? You're going to have more
political
stability, right? You're going to have
more political stability if one
administration is in power for 8 years
instead of 5 years. That is assuming
that we don't have the stupid
Westminster system in which you have
coalition government sometimes in which
there is no guarantee that a government
can last 8 years. But if you can
guarantee that a government lasts 8
years and you have an 8-year cycle, I
think it's great. We should try that out
for sure. So I agree with that. I mean,
it's a good
idea. Okay, with that, let us end
today's live stream. I really appreciate
all the questions. I thought the
questions were wonderful, most of them.
Uh, so thank you so much for all your
questions. We're going to have more of
these live streams next week. We're
going to have I think two or three
onehour live streams and one regular
like three-hour live stream next week
and next week's big live stream will be
on Saturday. Hopefully, I'll probably be
in good health. So, so once again, thank
you so much everybody. Uh keep learning,
keep asking questions, keep raising your
standards and I'll see you very soon in
next week's episodes which will all be
live episodes. Thank you so much. Good
day. Good night. Take care. Bye-bye.